Academia Sinica
中央研究院
Academia Sinica 11 six copies
中央研究院 11 六份
Machine Feast Lecture Begins
機事饗宴演講會開始
We ask Vice President Chen Jianren to host for us
我們請陳建仁副院長為我們主持
Director Liu Hudong
劉湖東所長
And some of our academicians here
還有我們在座的幾位院士
and ladies and gentlemen
還有各位女士、各位先生
good night everyone
大家晚安 大家好
today we are very happy
今天我們很高興
This knowledge feast of our Academia Sinica
這個我們中央研究院的知識饗宴
I can invite Director Liu Hudong
能夠請到劉湖東所長
Come talk to us about the topic
來跟我們做專題的
speech
的演講
So today is our admission to the Central South Hospital
那今天是我們中南院就院
This knowledge misses the record
這個知識想念破紀錄的
one day
一天
Because we have more than 300 applicants today
因為我們今天報名的有300多位
Then more than 100 colleagues from our hospital participated
那我們本院有100多位的同仁參加
Then there are 200 people outside the hospital
然後院外有200位
So wait a minute for those who are too late to come in
所以等一下來不及進來的人
There are other lecture halls where you can listen to lectures
還有別的演講廳可以來聽演講
So say we
所以表示呢我們
Director Liu is very attractive
劉所長是很有魅力的
first of all, let's keep it simple
那首先先簡單的來
introduce
介紹一下
Director Liu Budong
我們劉不東所長
Liu Yanshi's qualifications
劉燕氏的資歷
Academician Liu Budong
那劉不東院士
He graduated from the Chemistry Department of National Taiwan University in 1970
他是1970年畢業以臺大的化學系
Made in the United States in 1976
1976年取得美國
Ph.D. in Chemistry, University of Chicago
芝加科大學化學的博士
He then served
然後他曾經擔任過
Postdoctoral Researcher in Chemistry and Immunology
化學跟免疫學的博士後研究員
Then go to the famous Scripps in the United States
那就轉到了美國家座很有名的Scripps
Research center
研究中心
serve
任職
La Jolla Medical Research Institute
後來也到拉荷拉醫療研究院
research work
進行研究的工作
That's rare
那很難得的呢
ah
啊
this one at the time
這一個當時的
Dr. Liu is our present Liu Yansi
劉博士也就是我們現在的劉彥似
also during this period
也在這一段期間
He once studied at McAnney University in the United States
他曾經到美國麥安尼大學進修
This one achieved an MD
這一個取得了醫學博士
UCSD
又在加州聖地亞科大學
Receive specialist training in dermatology
接受皮膚科的專科醫師訓練
So he went from chemistry to medical dermatology
所以他從化學然後再到醫學皮膚科
Then he was at this Scripps research center
接著他在這一個Scripps研究中心
Bannon Associate Professor and Director, Department of Allergy Research
過敏研究部門班農副教授兼主任
Then at the Allergy-Level Academy of Fine Arts in La Jolla
然後在拉荷拉的過敏級美藝學院
Professor and Director of the Department of Allergy
的過敏部門的教授兼主任
In 2001, he was in the Daishi School in California, USA
2001年就在美國加州的代為十分校
Professor and Director of Dermatology
擔任皮膚科的教授兼主任
2011 as
2011年身為
This particular professor at U.C. Davis
這個U.C. Davis的特定教授
And is now an honorary professor at U.C. Davis
而且現在是U.C. Davis的榮修特定教授
The reason is because we are lucky
原因是因為我們很幸運的
Academia Sinica in 2011
中央研究院在2011年的時候
Can invite our director Liu Fudong
能夠邀請我們劉福東的所長
Mr. Liu
劉先生
Return to China to serve as the director of our biomedical institute
回國擔任我們生醫所的所長
I am a specific researcher
我當特定研究員
We also congratulate Director Yuan
我們也恭喜袁所長
This year he was elected as an academician of Academia Sinica
在今年他當選了中央研究院的院士
actually
實際上
Director Yuan's research on allergy
袁所長他在過敏方面的研究
Already well-known internationally
早就是國際很知名的
and made a lot of contributions
而做過很多的貢獻
For example, he has developed
譬如說他曾經發展出
can continuously separate IgE
可以不斷分立IgE
is one per globulin
就是每一球蛋白一的
At the beginning, I looked at the fusion game package strain
當初看體的融合遊戲包株
it's quite outstanding
這相當的傑出
in addition
另外
Director Yuan is studying the coagulation number of galactose
袁所長在研究半乳糖凝極數
you can listen to this part
可以來聽這一個部分
also feet
也是腳腳者
also sour
也是酸酸曲者
After he returns to our Academia Sinica
他目前回到我們中央研究院以後
Already with our biomedical institute
已經跟我們生醫所
and his colleagues in the Central Research Area
還有中央研究區他的同仁
promoted many large-scale studies together
一起推動很多大型的研究
including the relationship between gardens and disease
包括花園跟疾病的關係
That's today's topic
也就是今天的主題
There is also the part of Tang's biomedicine
還有唐類生物醫學的部分
Director Yuan is also presiding over Taiwan's
袁所長他現在也主持台灣的
Establishment of Biobank
生物資料庫的設立
with a very important impetus
帶有一個很重要的推動
Taiwan Biomedical Research
台灣生物醫學研究
and a job in the development of the biomedical industry
以及生物醫學產業發展的一個工作
That amount of shortening has served as a journal that is well-known abroad
那額縮長曾經擔任過在國外很有名的期刊
The Journal of Clinical Investigation
叫做《臨床研究雜誌》
Associate Editor, Jonathan Crane Co. Investigation
Jonathan Crane Co. Investigation的副編輯
And now it's famous
而且現在也是很有名的
The Journal of Dermatology
這一個皮膚科學雜誌
Editor-in-Chief of Jonathan Taurogyk's Science
Jonathan Taurogyk's Science的專項的主編
Of course Academician Liu has won numerous awards
劉院士當然獲獎無數
which also includes this
其中還包括了這個
University of California
加州大學代為師分校的
John O. M. Tinger Memorial Award
John O. M. Tinger的紀念獎
He gave a cancer and lung disease research
他是給了一個癌症跟肺病研究
this award
結出的這一個獎項
And it is our Taiwan dermatology department
而且是我們台灣皮膚科
A very important award from the Society of Dermatology
很重要的一個皮膚學會的一個獎項
Professor Li Yaoqing's Memorial Award
李耀清教授的紀念獎
Also an honorary member of our Taiwan Dermatology Association
也是我們台灣皮膚科醫學會的榮譽會員
Today we are very happy to invite Chief Luo to talk to us about
今天我們很高興請到羅首長來跟我們講
Today's keynote address Response and Disease
今天的主題發言反應與疾病
Is he our enemy or our friend
到底他是我們的敵人還是我們的朋友
a relationship
一個異敵異有的關係
that was a great speech
那這個很精采的演講
let us all applaud him
讓我們大家鼓掌歡迎他
Thank you, Dean Shengfu, for your introduction
謝謝升富院長的介紹
Thank you everyone, it's raining today
也謝謝各位今天天人下雨
listen to the speech here
在這邊聽這個演講
I am very very happy to have this opportunity
我很非常高興能夠有這個機會
share with you
跟各位分享一下
My response to this inflammatory response and disease
我對這個發言反應跟疾病的
some understanding of the relationship
關係的一些了解
I'm doing research
我在研究工作上面
Just now Dean Shengfu also mentioned that it is immune
剛才升富院長也提到是免疫
Also very interested in the response to the speech
還有對發言反應也很有興趣
In this regard, professional speeches have given
在這方面專業演講倒是給了
Quite many times, but the words of popular science is the first time
相當多次但是科普的話是第一次
Then I know I saw the statistics of this registration
那我知道我看到這個報名的統計
Many of them are business related
有不少是生意这方面的
I hope I'm not overly simplistic.
那希望我讲的不会说太简单化
that's not for that
那对于这方面并没有
It's also a stranger
也算是陌生的
That hopefully speaking can be understood
那希望的讲的可以是能够了解
then some gain
然后有些收获
the word that speaks
那发言这个字
In fact, it has been known for two thousand years
事实上知道已经是有两千年了
That's when you speak
那那个时候就是发言呢
it's a latin word called
它是一个拉丁字叫做
set to fire is to set fire to burn
set to fire 就是放火 烧起来
Then this is the word inflame
那这个就是inflame这个字
In fact, almost a century ago
那事实上到差不多一世纪前
almost 150 years ago
差不多150年前
Only then did the concept of that cell come in
才把那个细胞的观念放进来
put in this speech response
放进这个发言反应
Then you know how to speak and respond
那然后就知道说发言反应
Probably how to continue to start some
大概是怎么陆续续开始有些
Some of that new development understands
有些那个新的发展了解
but so of course
但是所以当然
So this statement response is not an update
所以说这个发言反应并不是更新
But what about the disease?
但是跟疾病的关系呢
is relatively new
是比较新
It's something that happened in the last twenty or thirty years
是最近二三十年的事情
found that many diseases
就发现说是很多疾病
can be explained by speech
可以用发言来解释
The disease used to be thought to be caused by something other than inflammation
疾病過去認為不是發炎的是其他的原因
Does the inflammation have something to do with the inflammation now?
那現在發炎是不是跟發炎很有關係
So today I will focus on the topic of inflammation.
所以我今天就是把這個題目就是發炎反應
with disease
與疾病
The first one to use this is a simple 30-second cartoon
那第一個先用這個一個簡單的30秒鐘的一個卡通
It's from Google
就是從Google當作下來的
That's what I think is inflammation towards this polarity
那就是我覺得往這個極性的發炎
I think it is a very simple and clear explanation
我覺得是一個很簡單而明瞭的一種解說
Then you see this is a capillary
那你們看到這是一個微血管
and then there is that blood
然後有那個什麼血
It's the red iron ball that will flow through
就是紅鐵球會流過去
sometimes white blood cells
有時候會有白血球
And then you'll find bacteria coming in
然後你會發現有細菌進來了
It's like a skin
這好像是一個皮膚吧
After bacteria enter under the skin
皮膚下面細菌進來之後
The bacteria also signal to make the microvascular cells
那細菌也信號會讓這個微血管的細胞
This time it is closed cells
這筆這次是管閉的細胞
it will react
它會反應
then here
然後這邊
Substances in the blood come out
血裡面的物質就跑出來
Then the next step is to let the blood vessels
然後接著就是讓血管
The other information is that its white blood cells will come out
另外的那些信息就是它的白血球會出來
Well, those are red blood cells, you can see that
好 那就是紅血球你們可以看得出來
Here comes the bacteria
那個細菌來了
Then it emits some signal
然後它會放出一些信號
The signal that the blood vessel knows will make some changes in the future
那血管它知道的信號以後它就會做些改變
Then here, some of its blood vessels
然後這邊的話它的血管裡面的一些
Some liquid still escapes
一些液體還跑出來
What about some substances in these bands?
那這些帶的一些物質呢
Combined with that bacteria
跟那個細菌會結合在一起
generate some more signals
又產生一些信號
Then this one will come out
那這一把也就出來了
it starts eating the cells
它開始吞食這些細胞
And the bacteria is clear here
而且這個細菌這邊清楚好
That's the acute origin reaction.
那這就是急性的發源反應
So the definition of origin reaction
那所以發源反應的定義
That is to say, the biological tissue is traumatized, internally injured
就是說是生物組織受到外傷、內傷
or patient infection
或是病人感染
Like just now, it was an example of a patient being infected
像剛才就是一個病人感染的例子
or reaction to exposure to irritating substances
或是接觸到刺激性的物質產生的反應
Then its tissue response is to include the red
然後它的組織的反應是包括了紅
Fever Pain Symptoms
種 發熱 疼痛 症狀
The reason for the redness is that the microvessels will expand
紅的原因是因為微血管會擴充
Then the blood is more expensive
然後血液流得貴更多
That's because blood is red
那就因為血液是紅色的
so it will have shallots
所以它會有紅蔥的
The tissue color of that part compares with red
那個部分的組織顏色比較和紅
In general, it is because the substances in the blood will escape from what I just said.
它總的話是因為剛才所說是血液裡面的物質會跑出來
If you have a fever, it is also related to blood circulation.
發熱的話也是因為跟血液循環有關
it's ours
它就是我們的
cold body temperature
cold body temperature
It spreads into the so-called injured tissue
它會發散到所謂的受到傷的細胞組織裡面
If there is pain, it is after these substances come out
疼痛的話也是這些物質出來之後
it affects the nerve endings
它會影響到神經的末梢
So in this following speech
所以在這個下面的演講裡面
I'll talk about it first
先會講一下
It is the relationship between avoiding the source and the inflammatory response
就是避源跟發炎反應的關係
then talk about trauma
然後講到外傷
Then talk about some irritating substances
然後講到一些刺激性的物質
Then talk about internal injuries
然後講到跟事實上之內傷
but some
但是是一些
For example, related to the heart
比如說是跟心臟有關的
related to angels
跟天使有關的
so high cool range
所以高酷的範圍
is brutal
是蠻管的
our human body
我們人體
not actually a human body
事實上不是人體
Even the D-Dent animals are the same
就是D-Dent動物也是一樣
just have this kind of resistance
就是都有這種抵抗
A mechanism of Defense
Defense的一個機制
like our country
就像我們國家
If there are foreign enemies
如果是有外來的敵人的話
we will know how to resist
我們會知道怎麼樣抵抗
This is the mechanism of resistance
這個就是抵抗的機制
depends on some immune system
是靠一些免疫的系統
So the immune response is closely related to the inflammatory response
所以免疫的反應跟發炎反應是息息相關的
There are two immune responses
免疫反應有兩種
an innate immune system
一種是先天的免疫的系統
One is a response called adaptation
一個是叫做適應的反應
Let me not mention it for now
適應我先暫時不提
innate immune words
先天免疫的話
The two protagonists are Nutriphil and Microphage
兩個主角是Nutriphil跟Microphage
This is the missing white blood cell
這個是失蹤性白血球
Megalithic cells
另外是巨石細胞
The missing white snowball
那失蹤性白雪球
in the blood
在血液裡面
You just saw that cartoon
你們剛剛看到那個卡通裡面
That is the missing white snowball coming out
那個就是失蹤性白雪球出來
it's in the blood
那它是在血液裡面
Of course, red blood cells are the most
血液裡面當然是紅血球最多
But the most white blood cells are
但是白血球的裡面最多的就是
It is Nilchffville
就是Nilchffville
missing white snowball
失蹤性白雪球
It is about one and a half times the size of a red blood cell
它的大小大概是紅血球的一倍半左右
it is a microscope image
它是顯微鏡像
If after dyeing
如果染色之後
You can see it has
你可以看到它有
it has several nuclei
它有幾片的細胞核
About five slices of three slices
三片的五片左右
why is it called neutral
它為什麼叫中性呢
That's because when dyed
那是因為染色的時候
Some cells are stained to become stained
有些細胞是染色的變成染色
some cells turn red
有些細胞變成紅色
That is, Basophil has Synophil
那也就Basophil 有Synophil
Then this is without Balve
那這個是沒有Balve
no no no no dyeing
沒有不是又不是染色
not red
又不是紅色的
it is equal to say neutral color
它就是等於說中色
So it's called Nilchffville
所以叫做Nilchffville
Then it was shown in the cartoon just now
那剛才那個卡通裡面顯示出來
It's Nilchffville that circulates in the blood
就是Nilchffville在血液裡面循環
Then when you get this signal
那還吃到這個信號的時候
It will leave the tissue from the blood circulation to dels
它會從血液循環離開到 dels的組織
At this time, there is a factor called driving factor
那這個時候有一個叫做驅化因子
Chimokai
就Chimokai
It is very important in this inflammatory response
它是在這個發炎反應裡面非常重要的
So I'm researching and researching addicts in this research
所以我在這個研究研究研究研 addicts
It will mention several cells
裡面會提到幾個細胞
most important
最重點
a few cells
一個幾個細胞
several molecules
幾個分子
Molecule is an important thing called Chimokai
分子就是一個重要的就是叫做Chimokai
So the driving factor
所以驅化因子
No need to know the details
詳細情形不需要特別了解
But I know that this protein
但就知道說這個蛋白質
because of its relationship
因為它的關係
Where will this white blood cell come out?
這個白血球才會出來到哪裡
know where to go
知道到哪裡去
then it just
然後它就
it's to this germy place
它是到這個有病菌的地方
Then it will put the germ
然後它就會把這個病菌
or swallow it
要不然吞食呢
or put it
要不然就是把它
kill that
把它那個殺掉
or it sucks it
或是它把它吸附住
there is a way
有一種方式
But its end result is that it will
但它最後的結果就是它會
it is against the germ
它是抵抗這個病菌
And finally eliminate the germs
然後把病菌最後消除掉
so this is
所以這個是
This is a
這是一個
in the inflammatory response
就是在發炎反應裡面
A very important cell is New Nufel
非常重要的一個細胞就是紐紐菲爾
This V6 is quite interesting
這個V6呢 蠻有意思的
quite famous now
現在蠻有名的
This is Snowball
這個是白雪球
This is the red snowball
這個是紅雪球
There's a New Nufel in here
那這裡面有一個紐紐菲爾
those are bacteria
那這些是細菌
Then he will know where the germs are
那他就會知道細菌的哪裡
He has been checking this bacteria
他就一直在這個check這個細菌
and finally swallow it
然後最後是會把它吞噬進去
that is not yet
那現在還沒有
right
對
slowly
慢慢了
And now he finally got this bacterium in
然後他現在終於這個細菌進去了
exists inside
就存在裡面
Then he found another
然後他又找到另外一個
Seems to be bigger bacteria
好像也是細菌比較大一點的
he used to devour it
他過去把它吞噬進去
so this is
所以這個是
That is, he has this real function
就是他有這個真實的這個功能
That's the first protagonist
那這是第一個主角
The second protagonist is the microphage
第二個主角是microphage
megalithic cells
巨石細胞
so is this
那這個也是一樣
It will eat the source of the disease
它是會把病源吃進去
and after eating
然後吃進之後
Same with Newfel in the world
跟世上紐紐菲爾也是一樣
I didn't say it just now
我剛剛沒有講
it has a
就它有一個
There are some called dragon body
有一些叫龍小體的
It will finally eat the source of the disease
它會最後會把這個病源吃進去
break it down
把它分解掉
products of decomposition it will come out
分解的產物它會出來
So in terms of this role of resisting the patient
所以在這種抵抗病人的角色上面的話
Neutral field is similar to migrophox
neutral field跟migrophox也是差不多的
it can eat it too
它也可以把它吃進去
It can also secrete some substances
也可以把它分泌出一些物質
kill these bacteria
殺死這些細菌
there is a difference
有一個差別
wait a minute i'll talk more
等一下我會再多講一下
But the difference is that it
但是差別就是說它
Because after this decomposition
因為這個分解之後
it is carried out in detail
它就是詳細進行
I don't think so
我想就不提
But in the end it was able to make that
但是它最後它能夠讓那個
I just mentioned that there is innate immunity
我剛提到說是有先天性免疫
Immunity to the adaptive response
跟那個適應性的反應的免疫
it will make that adaptive response
它才會讓那個適應性的反應
immune response will come out
免疫反應會出來
wait a minute
等一下再提
basically
基本上的話
These are the two neutral fields
就是這兩個neutral field
with migrophox
跟migrophox
They are the two protagonists doing the inflammatory response
就是在做發炎反應的兩個主角
So here the words
所以在這邊的話
It is said that the inflammatory reaction is the enemy or there is
說是發炎反應是敵或是有
It's obvious here
那這裡面很明顯的是
Because if you don't have these inflammatory reactions
因為如果說你沒有這些發炎反應
Without this neutrophil, without microphage
沒有這個neutrophil 沒有microphage的話
If there is a bacterial infection, there is no way to resist it.
那有細菌感染的話 就完全沒辦法抵抗
So this is an indispensable resistance mechanism of the human body
所以這是人體不能缺少的一種抵抗機制
Then this resistance mechanism reflects an inflammatory response
那這個抵抗機制反應出來是一個發炎反應
Another source of disease is the virus
另外一個病源是病毒
Viruses are slightly different
病毒的話就稍微不太一樣
The virus is when the human body knows that there is a virus infection
那病毒人體知道說是有病毒感染的時候
It has a polar cell
它這個有個叫極狀細胞
wait a minute i'll talk more
等一下我會再多談一下
So let's not talk about the polar cells for now.
所以先暫時不講這個極狀細胞
it makes two lymphocytes
它會讓兩個淋巴細胞
One for T cells and one for B cell activation
一個是T細胞 一個是B細胞活化
T cells then produce some cytokines
然後T細胞會產生一些細胞激素
I just talked about I just talked about a few cells
我剛剛講說我剛剛會講到幾個細胞
and then several substances
然後幾個物質
I just said that KIMOKAI is called the driving factor
就是刚刚讲KIMOKAI就是叫驱化因子
Cytokines
另外一种叫細胞基素
These two are the most important two in the inflammatory response
这两个就是发炎反应里面最重要两个
two ophthalmia
两个眼炎
cytokines and cytokines
就是細胞基素跟驱化因子
One is KIMOKAI and the other is cellular liver
一个是KIMOKAI一个是細胞肝
additionally activated cells
另外活化的細胞
T cells produce cytokines
T細胞会产生細胞基素
In addition, it knows when there is a virus infection
另外它知道有病毒感染时候
it becomes a cell body
它会变成叫做細胞体体
it kills other cells
它是会杀死其他細胞的
Viruses usually go inside cells
病毒通常会到細胞里面去
survive there
在那边存活
it can breed here
它这边可以繁殖
then there came out
然后有出来
This cell will know to say
这个細胞它会知道说
where is this virus
这个病毒在哪里
Then it poisons the cell
然后它把这个細胞毒杀
virus infected cells
病毒感染的細胞
So use this way to fight this virus
所以用这种方式来抵抗这个病毒
Another way is to use B cells
另外一方式就是用B細胞
B cells produce body
B細胞会产生看体
can synthesize virus
可以綜合病毒
So just said three
所以剛就講了三個
One is Neutral Fuel and Magavage
一個是Neutral Fuel跟Magavage
Two to fight the pathogen
兩個來抵抗這個病源
The other is to use 08 ball
另外就是用08球
08 cells to fight the virus
08細胞來抵抗這個病毒
These are also immune responses
這些也是免疫反應
But it is also possible to produce
但是也是可以產生
A basic process of the inflammatory response
發炎反應的基本的一個過程
good
好
That's what I just said
那這就是剛講的
It's the inflammatory response that we have
就是發炎反應是我們的有
we can't do without these
我們不能缺少這些
inflammatory response cells
發炎反應的細胞
or these bases
或是這些基數
Or that Kimokansalokan
或是那個Kimokansalokan
Then I believe in the following one
那我相信在下面講一個
I think it's a very good example of an inflammatory response.
我覺得是發炎反應非常好的一個例子
That is Injury Repair
那就是Injury Repair
That's after the wound
那是傷口受傷了以後
how do we get it back
我們怎麼樣讓它復原
That's because I'm a dermatologist
那因為我是皮膚科的
so i believe
所以我相信
The example I chose is also related to the skin
我選的例子也是跟皮膚比較有關的
more familiar
比較熟悉一點
So the mechanism of wound repair
所以傷口修復的機制
Generally speaking
一般說來
after being injured
受了傷之後
It can be roughly divided into three stages
大概可以分成三個階段
let the wound heal
讓傷口來修復
The first stage is Information
第一個階段是Information
so when you get hurt
所以一受傷的時候
Of course we know that said wounds have wounds
我們當然知道說傷口有傷口
But the first reaction is the inflammatory reaction
但第一個反應就是發炎反應
is an inflammatory reaction
就是發炎反應
This is a local inflammatory reaction
這是局部的發炎反應
I'll talk about the details later
等一下我細節會稍微再講一下
This is on the first day and the second day
這個在第一天第二天的時候
is a local inflammatory reaction
是局部發炎反應
Then there will be a process of cell proliferation
然後再來會有細胞增生的過程
Then finally the wound presynthesis matures
然後最後傷口預合成熟
This is about a week or so
這個是大概一個禮拜左右
A week or two here
這邊的話一兩個禮拜
But in fact it sometimes
但事實上這有的時候
If the wound is large, it can be repaired in it for a year.
大的傷口的話可以到一年還在裡面修復
and then again and again
然後才一次次在
let it finally mature
讓它最後能夠成熟
so here
所以這邊
The first is if
第一個就是如果是
here is a skin
這邊是一個皮膚
got hurt
受到傷了
so hurt
這樣受到傷
Of course the first feeling is
當然是第一個感覺是
So it should be seen that there is a suspension of school
所以應該是看到的是是有休學
Next, when I study abroad in human body
接下來我在人體留學的時候
The school version will come
學校版就會進來了
After the school version came in
學校版進來之後
Let's learn from the adjacent bone
就讓我們學鄰骨
So that's our body's first reaction
所以這是我們身體的第一個反應
This is not an inflammatory reaction
這個還不能算是發炎反應
But in fact the school version will also
但事實上學校版也會
also co-builds the inflammatory response
也會共建到發炎反應
I won't mention it anymore
那這我就不再提
Those two are the students of the school version
那二位是學校版的學生
what's next
那接下來呢
That means there are germs coming in.
就是說是有病菌進來
Then you might say
那各位也許會說
I actually wash my hands
我其實平常洗手
Although after the cut
雖然是割了傷以後
There should be no virus
應該沒有病毒吧
but it's really amazing
但是真的是非常奇妙
is our human body
就是我們人體
you don't know
你自己不知道
But let's say that the skin is not above
但是我們譬如說皮膚不上面
There are thousands of diseases
有成千成萬的病
the bacteria is on it
這個細菌在上面
is quite okay with us
跟我們是相當無事
we don't interfere with them
我們也不干擾他們
they don't bother us
他們也不干擾我們
commercial bacteria
commercial bacteria
it doesn't infect us
它不是會感染我們的
it's over there
它就在那邊
We correspond to co-existence
我們對應是共生存
Usually we don't even know
平常我們更不會知道
but when hurt
但是一受傷的時候
These germs will enter the human body
這些病菌就會進到人體裡面
At this time we will react
這個時候我們就會產生反應
just like our first cartoon
就像剛才我們第一個卡通一樣
After some bacteria come in
就是有些菌進來以後
White blood cells know how to kill the germs
白血球就知道怎麼樣去殺這個病菌
So it's the same here
所以這個情況這邊也是一樣
Invading germs attract white blood cells
入侵的病菌就會吸引到白血球進來
white blood cells first neutrophils
白血球先是中性顆粒細胞
It is neutrophil
就是neutrophil
So this is the first day
所以這是在第一天的時候
It's neutrophil coming
是neutrophil跑來
These neutrophils begin to clear these bacteria
這些neutrophil就開始清這些細菌
You see less and less bacteria
細菌你看越來越少了
mid term
中期的時候
It's called monocytes coming in here
以回叫做單核細胞進到這邊來
Then it becomes true after monocyte activation
然後就單核細胞活化以後變真
megalithic cells
巨石細胞
This is MACOFIG
這就是MACOFIG
Its predecessor is the monocyte
它的前身是單核細胞
called MALASIDE
叫MALASIDE
And then it can also help the gluteal stone invade the bacteria
然後它也可以幫助臀石侵入細菌
and dead tissue and blood cells
和死亡的組織和血球
That's monocytes
那這就是單核細胞
So in a few days or so
所以大概在幾天左右
monocytes come in
單核細胞進來
It then activates into a megalithic cell
然後它會活化變成巨石細胞
Here MACOFIG
在這裡MACOFIG
Then it goes on NUGIFILM
然後它繼續NUGIFILM
unfinished work
沒有完成的工作
And NUGIFILM died too
還有NUGIFILM也死亡了
it can swallow it up
它可以把它吞噬進去
I'll talk to you next time
接下來這邊就跟發言
not that relevant
不是說那麼有關
it always pre-cores
它就總是要預核
Pre-core is to fill in the missing tissue
預核的話就是填補缺失的組織
and pull into the sides of the wound
並拉進傷口兩側
Tissue that helps prenucleate to form eight scars
幫助預核形成8痕的組織
That's where the words are keratinocytes
那就是這裡的話是角質細胞
It still needs to be repaired here
這邊還是要修復才行
At this time, fibroblasts
那這個時候纖維母細胞
FIREBLAZE plays an important role
FIREBLAZE就在重要角色
it secretes
它會分泌
collagen , fibroelastin
膠原蛋白,還有彈性纖維蛋白
These words are here
這些的話就是在這邊
The wound can close him
傷口能夠把他預合
In other words, toe cells
另外的話就是腳趾細胞
This wound must also be pre-closed
也必須把這個傷口預合住
he moves and proliferates
他會移動,也會增生
Then here, the wound gets smaller and smaller
然後這邊,這個傷口就越來越小
In the end, it couldn't be seen that there was a wound
最後就看不出來是有傷口
so this is
所以這個是
In the end, the sawtooth cell will still be here
到最後,鋸齒細胞還是會在這裡
haven't left yet
還沒有離開
He continues to put some
他就在這邊繼續把一些
dead cells, debris
死亡的細胞,碎屑
and some excess scar tissue
還有一些多餘的疤痕組織
fix it again
再把它修復一下
It's like doing clean up work here
等於說在這邊做clean up的工作
so this is a
所以這是一個
just a really good one
只是非常好的一個
example of an inflammatory response
發炎反應的例子
So this is also, we say that the inflammatory reaction is in it
那這也是,我們說發炎反應在這裡面
are we have or low
是我們有或是低呢
should be there
應該是有的
Because if there is no inflammatory response,
因為如果說沒有發炎反應的話
The wound is not big
傷口就不大了
So it is a wound that needs to be pre-nucleated, starting with the inflammatory response
所以它是傷口要預核的話先從發炎反應開始
That's why there is this step by step like this
所以才會有這個一步一步這樣子
to the final pre-core
到最後預核
But if there is no word in the previous paragraph
但是前面這段沒有的話
It is more difficult to pre-nucleate the wound if it is inflamed.
就是發炎這個傷口就比較難預核
But the mechanism of this immunity
但是這種免疫的機制
Inflammation mechanisms also take a toll
發炎的機制也會代價
That's because it's hard to say how much is enough, right?
那因為很難講說多少才夠對不對
It's what we know we must have an inflammatory response
就是它我們知道我們一定要發炎反應
To be able to resist the virus from outside
才能夠抵抗外面來的病毒
Pre-nucleation requires an inflammatory response
需要發炎反應長國才會預核
But it's really hard to know how much is enough
但是實在是很難說是知道要多少才夠
that's not perfect
那不是perfect
So I now have an example
所以我現在有舉個例子
It is when the inflammatory response should have helped the host
就是當發炎反應本來應該是幫助這個host
Then for example in the case of inflammation in the case of infection
然後譬如在發炎在感染的情況下
but it's a little too much
但是它太過分了一點
So the result it gets is a problem for the human body
因此它得到的結果是對人體的問題
On the contrary, there is a great threat
反而是有很大的威脅
that's what i think you should remember
那這就是我想各位應該記得
10 years ago 10 years ago
超10年前已經10年了
SARS affected us a lot
SARS影響我們非常大
2002 to 2003
2002到2003年
In Asia, there are probably tens of thousands of this
那亞洲的話大概是上萬的這個
People are affected
人受到影響吧
The number of people with 100,000 is also nearly 1,000
那有10萬的人數也是將近1000
The damage to the economy is about 40 billion US dollars.
那經濟的損害也是到400億美元左右
This is a
這是一個
When I found this effect
當初找到了這個影響到
What caused SARS was a virus
造成SARS是一個病毒
Its name is the filling virus
它的名字叫做灌占病毒
Because you can see this under a microscope
因為在顯微鏡下可以看到這個
Some prominent structures like Huangguan Zhouyuan
像黃灌周圓的這種突出的一些構造
That's why it's called a filling virus
所以叫做灌占病毒
Then this was the serious infection caused by Taiwan
那這個是當初這個台灣造成嚴重的感染
Many hospitals closed their eyes
很多家醫院封眼
many people wearing masks
很多人戴著口罩
Then this is the sanitation of front and rear recognition
那這個是前認的前後認的衛生
The chief goes to the Peace Hospital
局長到和平醫院去
they dress inclusive
他們穿著包容
Airtight clothes to the hospital to see
密不透風的衣服到醫院去看
This is the original case
這個是當初的病例
About 600 to 700 people were affected
大概是六七百個人影響到
About 15% should be dead
應該是15%左右是死亡
So everyone should have
所以大家應該有上
The number of frontlines is unknown
前線數目不太知道
But there are about 300 deaths
但是大概有三百左右的死亡的個案
same as marching flu
跟遊行性感冒一樣
just have a fever and dizziness
就是會有發燒頭暈
temper oxygen headache
脾氣氧頭痛
muscular mature
肌肉成熟
throat cough etc.
喉嚨咳嗽之類的
But it's most important
但是它最重要的就是
After it is infected by the virus
它這個病毒感染之後
it affects the lungs
它會影響到肺
then pneumonia
然後會肺炎
when taking x-rays
照X光片的時候
It doesn't look like the pneumonia is very serious
看不出來肺炎非常嚴重
Some patients need a respirator to help keep him alive
有些病人就需要用呼吸器才能夠幫助維持他的生命
Then about 10 to 15% of the cases are infected and he will not survive
那有10到15%左右的病例感染了之後他會沒辦法生存
Then this is the inflammatory response of the human body to the infection of this virus
那這個就是人體對這個病毒的感染發生的發炎反應
And this inflammatory response is too strong
而這個發炎反應過強了
Therefore, it is called Sidokan stone at this time
那因此影響到這時候叫做Sidokan stone
It's a storm of cytokines
就是細胞激素的風暴
I just mentioned cytokines and this Hemokan
那剛剛我提到過是細胞激素還有這個Hemokan
is very important and plays an important role in the inflammatory response
是非常重要的在發炎反應佔重要的角色
But if he says it's too much
但是他如果說是過分多的時候
It is called Sidokan stone
才產生叫Sidokan stone
In this case
那這種情況下
This is Sidokan's exaggerated immune response
這是Sidokan的過度的免疫反應
or an inflammatory response that destroys tissue in the lungs
或發炎反應破壞了肺部的組織
The result was severe pneumonia.
那得到結果就是很嚴重的肺炎
In the following words, we will talk about inflammation, infection and wound repair
下面的話,會有講到發炎反應跟感染還有傷口的修復
Saying that he should be indispensable to this
講的說是他對這個應該是不可或缺的
But in a way, he was supposed to be helpful against the hospital
但是在某種情況下,他本來是應該對抵抗病院有幫助
But if he goes too far, it will affect life and be dangerous
但是他過分的話會影響到對生命是會有危險
I will now give a few other examples
我現在下面就講幾個另外的例子
So it turns out, they're talking about acute inflammatory reactions
這些就變成是,他們講的都是急性的發炎反應
Now let's talk about the chronic inflammatory response
現在再講一下慢性的發炎反應
Some things we've probably known from the past are inflammatory reactions.
有些事我們過去就大概知道是發炎反應
But I will talk about a few more examples later because I didn’t know about it in the past.
但是後面我再講幾個例子是過去並不知道
It is said that it is really caused by an inflammatory reaction.
說是真的是發炎反應造成的
It is now known that the inflammatory response plays an important role
現在知道發炎反應是很重要的角色
The first is the name
第一個是講過名
I think what I said earlier was about cell bacterial infection
我想前面的話講到細胞細菌感染
Then I think everyone in each district has experience with wounds
然後傷口我想各區各位都有經驗
If you are allergic, I think it is about ten or twenty percent.
過敏的話我想也是大概十幾二十個百分百的
So there will be allergies
所以都會有過敏的經驗
So there are probably a lot of faces when you are doing it.
所以在做各位臉大概有不少
is aware of the effects of allergies
是知道過敏的影響
this is an allergic reaction
這個是一種過敏的反應
Then it usually means that there are some substances around us
然後通常就是說在我們周遭有一些物質
should be humilus
是應該是humilus的
But our bodies still respond
但我們身體還是會反應
because it is forend
因為它是forend
But sometimes the reaction doesn't matter much
但是有的時候反應並沒有什麼太大的影響
But for this kind of humilus
但是對這種本來是humilus的
it produces this reaction
它產生這個反應
and the result of the reaction is an allergic reaction
而反應的結果會產生過敏
This substance we have to take care of is called allergy
這個物質我們就要顧就叫過敏炎
That's like skin contact
那比如說是跟皮膚接觸到的
It’s Lujiao’s Latex
是魯蕉這個Latex
or animal hair
或是動物的毛髮
Allergic skin reaction after contact with skin
接觸到皮膚之后让皮膚有过敏的反应
Some medicines in milk and milk can cause allergies
那牛奶和牛奶有些药物会产生过敏
Some of those are just that, for example, peanuts
那一些有些就是那个譬如说是花生啦
caused by other lotuses
其他的荷果造成
Also very commonly seen by allergists
也是非常通常见到的过敏员
I heard recently that it is, for example, a child recently
最近听说是就是譬如说是最近小孩子
This kind of allergy to this peanut is more and more
这种对于对于这个花生的过敏越来越多
It seems that it may be, for example, an inside
好像说是大概可能比如说一个里面
one in five
五个里面就一个
In fact, this allergy is getting more and more
那事实上是这个过敏越来越多
The reason for that is wait a minute we have a chance
那这个原因是等一下我们有机会
Maybe talk a little more about why we have more and more allergies
也许可以再谈一下为什么我们过敏会越来越多
that anyway
那这anyway
This is what causes allergies when you eat it
这就是这是吃的时候会产生过敏的
Sometimes by injection, medicine or honey
有的时候注射的话药物或是蜂蜜
The venom of the honey bee ran into the human body
蜜蜂蜜蜂那个那个毒液跑到人体
some people will be reborn
有些人就会反生
allergic reaction
產生過敏的反應
In addition, western words such as pollen
另外,西部的話比如花粉
i think some of you guys
我想有些,在座各位
Some of you will know from experience with hay fever
有些大家會知道是有花粉熱的經驗
black pneumonia
黑肺炎
That's because there are some proteins in the pollen
那是因為,花粉裡面有些蛋白質
to it will produce
對它會產生
It is some substance that should be homeless
它是一個應該是homeless的一些substance
But after you inhale
但是你們吸進去之後
had this allergic reaction
產生了這個過敏的反應
If the dust is not the dust itself
那灰塵的話,並不是灰塵本身
It's the mite inside the dust, which is full of dust
而是灰塵裡面的mite,就是塵滿
also an allergy
也是過敏的一種
that plum fungus, that has hair
那梅菌fungus,那都有毛髮
What about those allergies?
那這些過敏呢
usually begins in childhood
通常在小孩子的時候開始有
There are several different ways of expressing these
那這些有幾種不同的表現的方式
One is private, that is skin
一個是私人,就是皮膚的
odorous dermatitis
就是異味性皮膚炎
That's usually odorous dermatitis first.
那通常是異味性皮膚炎先出來
Then, at the same time
然後呢,再同時
In childhood, for example, at about six months, it can occur at about one to two years old, and the incidence rate is relatively high.
在小時候,比如說是六個月左右,就可以發生一至兩歲左右的發生率比較高
15 Over rice is another, also a kind of allergies
15過米是另外一個,也是過敏的一種
Then there will be wheezing, and finally rhinitis will come out
接著是會氣喘,然後最後鼻炎才會出來
This order is not necessarily like this, but most of them are like this, so this is called allergic march
這個順序不一定是這樣子,但是大部分是這樣子,所以這叫做allergic march
These are all related to an allergic disease
這些都是相關的一種過敏性的疾病
Fortunately, if you are allergic at 15, it usually disappears after a few years
好在15過敏的話,通常幾歲之後就沒有了
This treatment will also gradually improve, and the same is true for breathlessness.
這個施整的話也是會慢慢好,氣喘的話也是一樣
Rhinitis will be easier to continue until adulthood
鼻炎的話到時候會比較容易延續到成人的時候還是會有
Of course, these all start when you are an adult, and there are also such
這些當然都是在成人的時候開始,也是有這種的
Let's talk about allergic reactions
再講一下過敏的發炎反應是怎麼樣
just mentioned
剛剛提到過
B is 08 cells, two of them are T and B
B是08細胞,有兩個是T,又是B
Let's talk about B cells first
我們先講B細胞
B cells produce antibodies
B細胞產生抗體
For example, IGM, IGG, the most IGG, IGA
比如說是IGM,IGG,IGG最多的,IGA
In addition, the least is IGE
另外比較最少的是IGE
This IGE produced an over-reaction, the most important role
這個IGE就產生過篇反應,最重要的一個角色
IGE antibody
就是IGE抗體
IGE has a special feature, it is another cell
IGE有特別特色,它就是另外的細胞
It's related to allergic reactions, yes, it's related to anti-antireactions.
跟過敏反應,對,就是反對抗反應有關的
And it's very related to allergic reactions, called mast cells
而且跟過敏反應很有關係的,叫做肥大細胞
That's called MASO
那叫做MASO
IGE will have its receptors on this
IGE會在這上面有它的受體
so it attaches to the mast cells
所以它會吸附在肥大細胞上面
If this is true, it is wrong, it should be the other way around
這上是真的話錯了,它是應該是反過來了
reverse like this
像這樣反過來
It is anti-inflammatory and allergic
它這邊是會節到抗炎,過敏炎的
Connect to this MASTER
接到這個MASTER上面去
Then the allergic person in
然後過敏人在
these are allergies
這些都是過敏人
allergic person
過敏人
Then when you see someone with allergies
然後在看到過敏人的時候
He will activate this MASTER
他就會把這個MASTER活化
MASTER will generate
MASTER就會產生
like organizing MMA
比如像組織MMA
There are other substances that can be called sensitive
還有其他能夠叫做敏感的一些物質
I think everyone has heard of this HISTOMINE
這個HISTOMINE我想大家都聽過了
would be called, say, WT runny nose
會叫做比如說WT流鼻水
just shed tears
就是流眼淚
or red eyes
或是眼睛紅這個
These phenomena
這些現象
that's sensitive
這就是敏感的
It's a sensitive reaction
就是敏感反應
THAT HISTOMINE IS IMPORTANT
那HISTOMINE是重要的
important cause of sensitivity
重要的造成敏感的原因
that's a little bit deeper
那稍微再深一點
It is how the BBC bag is made to cause IGE
就是BBC包怎麼製造造成IGE呢
Because it is the control of T cells
因為是T細胞的控制
So T cells are more commanding
所以T細胞是有比較發號適令的
this cell
這種細胞
It will talk to the BBC package
它會跟BBC包講說
You have to develop antibodies
你偏要必須要產生抗體
And I first T cells will talk to the BBC package
而我先T細胞會跟BBC包講說
You have to create antibodies that are IGE
你要造成抗體是IGE的
How do T cells know that there are these fermenter forces?
T細胞有怎麼知道有這些發酵者勢力呢?
Another very important cell, this should probably be Commander
另外一個很重要的細胞,這大概應該是Commander
It is called looking at the source and presenting cells, that is, Energy Preserving Cells
它是叫看源呈現細胞,就是Energy Preserving Cells
The other name is Dendry Cell, which is called polar cells
另外這個名字是Dendry Cell,就是叫做極狀細胞
The reason for the polar shape is because it is born like a touch shake, called Dendry Cell
極狀的原因是因為它這邊就是像觸摇一樣生出來,叫Dendry Cell
This is a very important cell
這個是非常重要的一種細胞
Talking about a gap is last year's Nobel Prize
講一個差距就是去年的諾貝爾獎
Given to Ross Diamond of Immunology at Rockupill University
給的是給的Ross Diamond Rockupill大學的免疫學的
It is because it discovered Dendry Cell, so it holds the Nobel Prize
它就是因為它發現了Dendry Cell,所以它拿著諾貝爾獎
But sadly, it's also fun
但是可惜的,也算是有趣的
It was actually three days before the price was announced, it was too much
它事實上是在那個Price公佈前三天,它過分
Then this inner guard card is usually not given to the deceased.
那這個內衛牌通常是不給過世的
It's not the one who lives now that will be given again
不是現在活的才會再給
when we were inside
當初我們在裡面
Because everyone knows that he is not in good health
因為大家知道他身體不太好
In fact he is a handicapped cancer
事實上他是遺障的cancer
But the committee member of the inner guard
但是內衛的那個委員
he is not sure
他不太確定
don't know his illness
不知道他的身病
His hands are already ashamed
他的手已經是隱愧
that close
那個接近
Didn't know he was dead when it was announced
在公佈的時候不知道他已經過世
But he finally decided to give him
但他最後決定還是給他
Give this award to his kid guest
給他的小孩來賓這個獎
Although his contribution is very large
他的貢獻雖然非常大
Also because he studies this
同時因為他研究這個
This is a very important cell
這個是非常重要的一種細胞
I just said he gave orders
我剛才說他發號適令
So it is very important in the immune response
所以在免疫的反應裡面是很重要
doing that now
現在在做那個
character award like this
人物獎這樣
like cancer
像cancer 癌症
but i won't say a word
但是我不會講一句就是
cancer treatments
癌症的治療方法
One way is to
有一種方法就是
See how we can use our immune system
看看我們怎麼樣能夠用我們的免疫系統
look at cancer
來看癌
that it because
那它因為
But this becomes a very important type of cell
但這個就變成很重要的一種細胞
Then it's because of research on this
那它因為研究這個的
So it uses its own cell
所以它就自己用自己的這個細胞
to treat my pancreatic cancer
來治療自己的那個胰臟癌
Turns out it actually works for it
結果它事實上是對它是有用的
So it only gets after pancreatic cancer
所以它只得到胰臟癌之後
it survived for about five or six years
它生存了大概五六年
five or six years
五六年
just passed away
才過世
If it doesn't have this
那它沒有這個的話
i don't think it can get it
我想它拿不到
nobel prize
諾貝爾獎
Because the Nobel Prize is
因為諾貝爾獎就是
always have to wait a few years
總是要等幾年
after knowing its fruit
知道它的成果以後
to give it
才能給它的
But it is a pity that in
但是很可惜的就是在
three days before the announcement
就是公布前三天
it passed away
它過世
it doesn't know itself
它自己沒有自己不知道
so it got the nobel prize
所以它拿到諾貝爾獎
That's almost
那這個差許
OK, that's strictly normal
OK 那嚴格正常就是
it this is a
它這個是一個
also a cartoon
也是一個卡通
it's an allergic reaction
就是過敏反應
mast cells
剛剛講的肥大細胞
it's a mast cell
它是肥大細胞
This is sealed venom, entering this is a Myself
這個是密封的毒液,進到這個是一個Myself
And there's a lot of Grammy that produces Histamine
然後這邊有很多產生Histamine的Grammy
There's particles over here, this is IgE, this is allergen
有顆粒在這邊,這是IgE,這是過敏元
After receiving its signal, it will enter
接到以後它的訊號會進去
Then these particles with Histamine will be expelled
然後這些有Histamine的顆粒會排出來
that is an allergic reaction
那就是造成過敏的反應
That is the Histamine tissue plant
那就是Histamine組織栽
But the cartoon is not actually right either
但這個卡通事實上也不對的
So sometimes you're being a tribute at Google and it's not always completely
所以有時候你在Google當個禮和不見得是完全
is completely convinced that this is true
是完全相信這個是對的
Because of its Histamine release
因為它的Histamine release的時候
The cell is alive, it just takes its Histamine out
細胞是活著的,它只是把它Histamine出來
But the cells still survive
但細胞還是一樣是survive
But the change is as if the whole cell becomes scattered
但是變化出來說是好像整個細胞就變成分散
This is actually not true
這個事實上並不是正確的
It's related to allergies, it's related to B yuan, it's asthma
那跟過敏,跟它跟B元有關的是氣喘
Asthma is more serious than
氣喘是比嚴重一點
because it is sometimes hard to breathe
因為它是有時候會呼吸困難
This is what it looks like when the trachea is normal
這個是在氣管正常的時候這樣子的
This is the trachea
這邊是氣管
This is the respiratory tract
這個是這邊是呼吸道
when panting
在氣喘的時候
One is why you are short of breath
一個就是為什麼會氣喘
A big reason is that it has Bronco Contrusion
一個重要原因是它是有Bronco Contrusion
it's muscle tension
就是它肌肉緊張
So its trachea constricts
因此它這個氣管就收縮了
Once it shrinks, it passes through and becomes much smaller
一收縮以後它是通過就小了很多
so it's hard to breathe
因此就是呼吸就會困難
so the cause of asthma
所以造成氣喘的原因
But this is in the past, for example, more than 30 years
但這個是過去比如30多年
when it comes to breathlessness
如果講到氣喘的話
Everyone said this is the reason
大家就說這個就是原因了
but now we know
但現在的話我們知道
In fact, it is such an important role as Information
事實上是Information這樣很重要的角色
Information For example, the production of its mucus
Information比如說它這個黏液的產生
also cause difficulty breathing
也造成呼吸困難
also because of the inflammatory response
也是因為發炎反應的關係
In addition is
另外就是
maybe not easy to imagine
也許不太容易想像
but in the process
但是在這個過程中
In fact, it is equivalent to having injury in this part
事實上是等於是在這個部位有injury
I just said that inflammation is trauma, internal injury
我剛講說發炎反應是外傷、內傷
This can also be thought of as a kind of internal injury.
這個也可以想把它講做是一種內傷
This internal injury is actually caused by an inflammatory response.
這個內傷事實上是發炎反應造成的
So which is the cause and which is the effect
所以是哪個是因哪個是果
it is hard to distinguish
它是很難分別
but what if
但是不然怎麼樣
Here's what caused it in the first place
就這邊是最先是什麼原因造成的
not sure
不太確定
But with this inflammation
但是有了這個inflammation之後
after inflammation
有發炎之後
It's going to be kind of hurt over here
這邊就會有點像受傷一樣
Repay after injury
受傷以後就要repay
But it keeps hurting and repaying
但是它一直受傷一直repay
The final result is that the lining on this side is getting thicker and thicker.
這個最後結果就是它這邊的lining越來越厚
The thicker the pain the less
越來越厚的痛苦就更小了
Plus it's smaller after muscle tension
再加上肌肉緊張以後它更小
So it's hard to breathe at this time
所以這個時候到最後呼吸困難
So it is also a relationship between inflammation and disease
所以也是一個發炎反應跟疾病的關係
words here
在這裡的話
I didn't know why these patients had some inflammatory reactions
本來是不曉得為什麼會這些病人會有些發炎反應
But in the end the inflammatory response is what affects the disease
但最後發炎反應是影響到這個病
And let this disease to the end and even to the extent of life
而讓這個病到最後甚至到生命的程度
That inflammatory response plays a big role
那發炎反應占了很大的角色
good
好
So what about national treatment and prevention?
那所以國民治療跟預防呢
In this raw material, what I want to talk about is
在這個原料裡面我想要講到就是
We learn more and more about the inflammatory response
我們對發炎反應的了解越來越多
The development of science is really long-term
科學的發展真的是長期性的
Maybe you won't see it in the short term
也許短期你也看不出來
But like this allergic reaction
但是像這種過敏反應
I used to know that there was such a reaction
過去知道是有這種反應
Gradually know what kind of cell I am
慢慢知道我大概是什麼樣的細胞
For example, mast cells
比如說是肥大細胞這些
What about this progress?
那這個進步呢
will let us know how to treat
就會讓我們知道應該怎麼樣治療
And here is a good example
而這邊也是一個很好的例子
so it's farther away after
所以它遙遠越多之後
Our treatment methods are getting better and better
我們治療方法就越來越前進
that's just generally speaking
那只是一般說來
we want a cure
我們要治療方法
One is to avoid allergens
一個是避開過敏源
Of course, if there are no allergens
當然是沒有過敏源的話
not sensitive
就沒有敏感
but it's hard to do
但是這個很難做到
then follow some statement
然後按照一些聲明
It depends on the organization
就是看組織安的
For example, I want this
比如說是我想這個
I think you have some
我想各位有些
Maybe use this too
也許也是用這個來
to sustain this statement
來維持住這個發言的
sensitive reaction
敏感的反應
That kind of estimation is very effective
那類估神非常有效
it has many side effects
它有很多的副作用
The method of desensitization
那減敏的方法的話
just if you know it's
就是如果你知道它是
sensitive to what
對什麼敏感源
is sensitive
就是敏感
You can use the doctor will take allergens
可以用醫生會拿敏感源
very small doses
非常小的劑量
inject it
注射進去
Then slowly increase the dose
然後慢慢把這劑量增加
and after a while
然後隔一陣子之後
this body
這個身體
know exactly why
完全知道什麼原因
The amount of IgE is getting less and less
那個IgE的量就越來越少了
That's why you're allergic to this one
那因此過敏的這個
less and less
現象也就越來越少
so this is one way
所以這是一種方式
this very old way
這個蠻古老的方式
but still continue to use
但現在還在繼續用
But what I want to say most is
但是我最想講就是
Antibodies against IGE
就是抗IGE的抗體
this latest
這個最新的
is a recent development
就是最近的發展
Then this Professor Zhang Ziwen
那這個張子文教授
He is also on this
他也是在這個上面
His company at the time, Tennox
他那時候的公司Tennox
Later, I cooperated with Ginetic two
後來跟Ginetic兩個合作
developed this
發展出來這個
called Omalizma
叫做Omalizma
or one of his
或是一個他的
Also called Zoleia
也叫Zoleia
But these antibodies
但是這些抗體
He can
他會
just to see the IGE
就是看到IGE
And let the IGE let the IGE
而把IGE讓IGE
won't be able to have his activity anymore
不會不能再有他的活性
So draw it here
所以這邊畫出來
This is IGE
這是IGE
Then this Anti
那這個Anti
Antibodies against IGE
就是抗IGE的抗體
So both of them are antibodies
所以他兩個都是抗體
One is IGE
一個是IGE
One is an antibody against IGE
一個是抗IGE的抗體
So this IGE
所以這個IGE
was supposed to be responsible for the mast cell
本來應該是負責在肥大細胞
and then finally make this
然後最後會讓這個
mast cell activation
肥大細胞活化
Then the organization comforted and ran out
然後那個組織安慰跑出來
but now he won't let him
但現在他不讓他
This is passed by the Department of Health in the United States to let him treat this Qishuang
這個在美國的衛生署通過了讓他治療這個氣爽
In addition, it must be effective for rhinitis
另外他對鼻炎一定是有效的
rhinitis is relatively
鼻炎是比較
Rhinitis may not be completely IgE
鼻炎不見得是完全是IgE
So his main effect may not be useful to everyone
所以他的要效不見得是對每個人都有用
But it should be useful for rhinitis
但是對鼻炎的話應該是有用
Just say if you need to use this
只說是不是需要用這個
Because he has a lot of sense of safety from organization N, Histamine can use it
因為他有很多看組織N的這些安感Histamine就能夠用
Also he has food allergies which should help too
另外他對食物過敏也應該是也有幫助
Another example we are talking about is Solitis
另外在講的一個例子就是Solitis
It's also a skin disease
這也是皮膚病
Also because I'm a dermatologist
也是因為我是皮膚科醫師
So I would like an example of a couple of skins
所以我想在幾個跟皮膚有關的一個例子
I think 10% to 20% of people have the sensitivity just mentioned
剛剛提到的敏感我想應該是10% 20%人有
Less for Solitis
Solitis的話就少一點
In Europe and the United States, it is 2%-3% of the population
在歐美的話是2%-3%的population
will be dangerous
會有感險
For Taiwan, this number is 0.2%
台灣的話,這數目是0.2%
I think it's a little on the low side
我覺得這偏低了一點
i think it should be
我想應該是
if it's that low
如果真的這麼低的話
should have gone
應該有去就是
maybe an epidemic
也許是流行病
Experts should just look at
專家應該就是看看
Do you know why it is so low
是不是知道說為什麼會這麼低
but i think it should be
但是我覺得應該是
about the same
跟這個差不多的
So this figure is not reliable
所以說明這個數字不可靠
so probably
所以大概是
I think it is
我覺得是
words from all over the world
全世界講來的話
About 2%-3%
大概是2%-3%
This is a recurrent chronic dermatitis
這是一種反復發作的慢性皮膚炎
recurrent in fact
反復發作事實上
it is in fact
它事實上是
If there is such a risk
有這個感險的話
is a lifetime
是一輩子的
but it's better sometimes
但是它有的時候會好一些
especially if you heal
尤其是你治療的話
but even if
但是即使是說
After getting better
轉好以後
it will also be in
它也會在
one for treatment and one for medicine
一部治療,一部用藥的時候
it will recur
它就會在反復發作
but it's not contagious
但是它不是傳染性的
the skin will thicken
那表皮會增厚
Then there is the thick cuticle
然後有營血狀的厚角質
vicious door bubble
惡毒門泡
Another name is medical disease
另外一個名叫做醫學病
on this epidermis
在這個表皮質上
Needle skin has more capillaries
針皮的話是有更多的微血管
then inflammatory cells
然後發炎細胞
can be seen inside
在裡面可以看得到
So it's an inflammatory response
所以這是一種發炎反應造成的
a skin disease
一種皮膚病
The skin of the whole body will be affected
全身的皮膚都會影響到
For example, the skin includes buttocks, nails
譬如說皮膚包括臀皮、指甲
more importantly
比較重要的是
We now know it's not just the skin that's affected
我們現在知道不只是皮膚受到影響
It's a Metabolic syndrome
它是個Metabolic syndrome
it's blood generation syndrome
它是代血綜合症
So we need to pay attention to these patients
所以這些病人的話我們就要注意到
heart problem is it diabetes
心臟的問題它是不是糖尿病
Usually they are a bit fatter
通常他們都會比較肥胖一點
so it is
所以它是
What we now know about this inflammation
現在我們對這種發炎的了解以後
It's also related to inflammation
這也是跟發炎有關
Although skin inflammation
雖然是皮膚的發炎
but it affects the whole body
但它會影響到全身
So now there's a fluke
所以現在有個致僥
There is a name called blood generation syndrome
有個名稱叫做代血綜合症
the patient
這個病人
Under this example
在這個例子下
It affects 80% of the skin
它是在80%的皮膚都影響到
very serious
非常嚴重的
Look at this in recent years
這個近年看
This is what it shows
這就是它的顯示
this is the slice
這是切片
Microscope to see
顯微鏡要看
Normal skin probably slightly
平常的皮膚大概稍微
at most this thick
最多這麼厚
this word
這個的話
Much thicker than normal skin
比正常皮膚厚了很多
Here are the ones with inflammatory reactions
這邊都是發炎反應的那些
responding cells
反應的細胞
if dyeing
如果做染色的話
you can see the cells that are inflamed
你就可以看到發炎反應的細胞就更明顯
these are here
這些就是這邊是有
quite severe inflammatory reaction
相當嚴重的發炎反應
then cause the skin cells
然後造成皮膚細胞的
multiply and become thicker
繁殖跟變成變厚
This is probably the most complicated one in my original house.
這個大概是我原家裡面最複雜的一張
So what I said earlier
所以前面我講的
reduce it a bit
都把它減少一點
That is, what is the reaction to Mingchang?
就是明改反應是怎麼樣的
here
這裡面
let's talk a little bit more
我們稍微講多一點
because i want
因為我想
You probably know a little bit more about it just now
剛才你們大概已經多了解了一下
Each page responds to the manufacture of B cells and T cells
這個每一頁反應B細胞T細胞的製造
So we're a little bit under Adventure
所以我們稍微在Adventure下
The ones below this one won't be reclaimed anymore
這個下面的不會再征復了
Another thing is
另外一件就是
here is a good story
這邊是一個很好一個故事
is the development of our treatment of tinea liver
就是我們對肝癬的治療的發展
It's true, it's our scientific development
是真的是就是我們科學發展的
a good example
一個很好一個例子
help with this disease
對這個治療疾病的幫忙
So the words of the hand cancer doctor
所以手癌師的話
It also starts with external stimuli
也從外面的刺激開始
There will be internal injuries after stimulation
刺激之後會有裡面的受傷
It’s not necessarily obvious what kind of stimulation it is
這個不見得說是很明顯是怎麼樣的刺激
but always hurt
但是總是有些受傷
That is, the cells in the dermis will be injured
就是細胞的真皮裡面會有受到傷
or some infection
或說是有些感染的時候
Finally, the extremely strong cells will activate
最後就是極壯的細胞會活化
this is what i just said
這就是我剛講的
He's the whole guy who stays on the 18th
他整個是一個待在18號施令的
equal to oneself
等於自己
This is equal to itself, it will secrete
這個等於自己它會分泌
For example, this is cytokine
譬如說這個是細胞激素
Cytokines
細胞激素
In fact there are dozens of
事實上現在有數十種
I just said
我剛講到就是
Sarcolemmal Liver Cheek Liver
肌膜肝 腮部肝
This is the cheek liver
這是腮部肝
now in fact there is
現在事實上有
There are about 30 known cheek livers
有知道的腮部肝大約有三十多個
Immunology
免疫學
getting richer
越來越富裁
Cells are not just cells
細胞不只是逼細胞
Kick cells come in a variety of
踢細胞有各種不同的
I won't talk about it today
我現在今天又不談
Cheek Liver, Cheek Liver as well
腮部肝 腮部肝也是一樣
not just one or two
不只是一兩個
Instead, there are dozens of
而是有數十種
but for this
但是對這個
love is understanding
所愛是了解的話
we just say yes
我們就說是
Focus at I-12 I-23
Focus at I-12 I-23
These cause the proliferation of kick cells
這些會造成踢細胞的增生
this kick cell
這踢細胞
and then secrete
然後再會分泌
other cytokines
其他的細胞激素
It's called Interferon Gamma
就是叫Interferon Gamma
or TNF Alpha
或是TNF Alpha
These will have two different effects
這些會有兩種不同的作用
One is inside the tissue cells
一個是繞織細胞裡面
Let the surrounding tissue cells secrete some other substances
讓繞織細胞分泌一些其他的物質
or let the tissue cells proliferate
或是讓繞織細胞增生
That's why the epidermis on the cell side becomes thicker.
所以細胞這邊這個表質才會變厚
It also makes the blood vessels respond
它會也會讓血管有反應
And the first cartoon is when the germs come in
然後最先的卡通就是細菌進來的時候
Vascular reaction, the white blood cells will come out
血管反應那個白血球會出來
the same here
這邊也同樣的
Because these cells produced by this T cell
因為這個T細胞產生的這些細胞
It's low speed, it will stimulate the blood vessels
就是低速它會刺激到血管
The mononuclear spheres inside will come out.
這個裡面的單核球就跑出來了
Then the mononuclear sphere still has the original myocytes
那這單核球出來還有原來的肌狀細胞
They also produce TNFF like this one
他們也會產生TNFF跟這個一樣
It also causes the secretion and proliferation of pericytes
也造成繞織細胞分泌及增生
Then here the dry display is generated
然後這邊乾顯就產生出來了
So this is a dry and pathogenic muscle transfer
所以這是乾顯致病的肌轉
That's what has been studied over the years.
那這也是多年來有很多的研究的
Do step by step turn this into this
做一步一步把這個變成這個
As the mechanism of the
作為的機制有更多的了解
Let me talk about this a little bit more
那這個我稍微再講一下
is a disease
就是疾病
that's why this stimulus
就是為什麼是這個刺激
clinically
在臨床上是
is there some kind of phenomenon
是有一些什麼樣的現象
That is, if hand cancer is almost cured
就是如果說手癌是已經差不多治好
Or you just have some skin diseases
或者說是你原來就是有一些有皮膚病
part of it doesn't
有一部分沒有
But if you get hurt over there
但那邊如果受傷的話
That part will still come out at that time
那一部分那個時候還是會出來
Hepatic glands are also shown
肝腺也會顯示出來
So say this is right
所以表示這個是對的
after stimulation
刺激以後
How to cause the activation here is not sure
怎麼樣造成這邊的活化不太確定
But there is a way
但是確實是有一種方式
let this show it's an irritation an injury
讓這顯示出來是一種刺激一種受傷
that just said
那剛講過
that liver gland is
那個肝腺是
yes
是
Cardiometabolic Neutralization Syndrome
每台胞胃心容代謝中和症
So it's not just
因此它不只是
liver gland
肝腺
It's inflamed
它這個發炎呢
hepatic glandular arthritis
會導致肝腺性的關節炎
Usually the hepatic glands start first
通常是肝腺先開始
say ten years later
比如說十年之後
These arthritis will come out
這些關節炎才會出來
not everyone will
不是每個人都會
For example, one hundred and twenty percent would
比如說是百分之十百二十人會
have this arthritis
會有這種關節炎
quite serious
蠻嚴重的
that diabetes
那糖尿病
More patients with hepatic glands
有肝腺的病人比較多
then in the liver
然後在肝
People with hepatic glands usually
通常有肝腺人
They are also more likely to see obesity
他們也是比較容易看到有肥胖
Then these are Metabolic syndrome
那這些都是Metabolic syndrome
It's all about inflammation
也都跟發炎有些
direct or indirect relationship
直接或間接的關係
What about the treatment?
那治療方式呢
the traditional treatment
就是傳統治療方式
lots of lotion
有很多的乳液
salve for inner lips
內部唇的藥膏
you can imagine
這個你可以想像
If the whole body has it
如果說全身都有的話
it's going to be very difficult
這要非常困難
Apply this to this clean place
把這apply到這個有乾淨的地方
off line treatment
那關線的治療
This is usually done with UV light
這通常是用紫外線來做
this is local
這是這局部的
But it can also be done for the whole body
但是也可以做全身的
the stomach medicine
那口腹藥的話
It is Metroflexid
就是Metroflexid
pretty strong medicine
蠻強的藥
But it has some side effects, such as the liver, not cause hepatitis
但是它有一些副作用,比如說對肝,不是會造成肝炎
The recent progress is like this, which advertises the treatment
那最近的進展是這樣子,那標榜治療
Just now I mentioned the method of TNF, TNF is Trumer Necrosis Factor
剛剛我提到過TNF的方法,TNF就是Trumer Necrosis Factor
here, here oh, here
在這裡,在這裡喔,這邊
I'll talk about TNF Alpha later when I talk about Trumer
等一下我講Trumer的時候,再會講一下TNF Alpha
very important cell technology
非常重要的細胞技術
So these pharmaceutical companies want to say that since TNF Alpha can cause hepatitis to hepatitis
那所以這些藥廠,它就想說,既然TNF Alpha對肝炎會造成肝炎
So should we also make this antibody to cover it
所以我們是不是也做這個antibody抗體,來把它包住
just make it inactive
就讓它沒有活性
The IGE we just talked about has antibody antibodies, preventing IG from acting
剛剛我們講的IGE,有antibody抗體,不讓IG作用
Similarly, antibodies can also be made
同樣的,也可以做抗體抗體
Don't let this TF Alpha work
不讓這個TF Alpha作用
So he can't do anything to affect the keratinocytes
因此就是他就沒辦法做影響到這個角質細胞
Then this is the first company made by Sentako
那這是第一個公司是Sentako做出來的
At this time, it was because of the antibodies produced in the mice
那這個時候他是因為現在老鼠裡面做出來的抗體
So he later had part of the mouse protein
所以他後來有一部分是老鼠的蛋白
The other company is Ebbett
那另外一公司是Ebbett
He turned him into an antibody that is all Human
他就把他變成全部是Human的人的抗體
The other company belongs to MGN
那另外一公司是MGN的
He does it with his receptors
他是用他的受體來做
Because his receptors are supposed to surround TF Alpha
因為他的受體本來就是會包圍住TF Alpha
Don't let him say let him not work
不讓他可以說讓他不作用
It can only work on cells
這在細胞上面他才可以作用
But if he divides it out, it is not on the cell
但他如果把它分出來不在細胞上面
But when he took it out, he would wrap it up to prevent him from functioning.
而當初拿出來的時候他會把它包住不讓他作用
So these are the drugs made by these three different pharmaceutical companies
所以這些就是這三個不同藥廠做出來的藥
Now patients with clean stomachs can use it
現在肚子乾淨的病人都可以用的
Then this is a pharmaceutical factory
那這個是一種藥廠
Twice a week used to be like inserting medicine
一周两次是过去像比如说插药的话
plug in every day
每天都要插
That said, it's only been about three months
那这个的话刚开始三个月左右
twice a week
一周两次
But then once a week is fine
但后来一周一次就可以了
That's every two weeks
那这个话是两周一次
That was about two or three years ago
那最近大概两三年前
Another company made this one from Synical
另外一公司这个是Synical做出来的
It acts on i12 and 23
它是把i12跟23作用的
then come back here
那回到这里
Here are the packed cells
这边是就是集装细胞
It was first clearly 12 and 23
它最先分明是12跟23
and then cause these reactions in the later stage
然后才造成后来的后段的这些反应
Then what their company does is
那他们这公司做的就是
just made antibodies
就是做出了抗体
i12, i23 able to get lost
能够迷路的i12、i23
Then this is the injection of the patient
那这个就是病人打一针
Then call again in a month
然后再过一个月之后再打一次
Then every three months
然后每三个月打一次
It becomes four times a year
就变成一年直四次了
four times a year
一年直四次
I can fight myself
自己可以自己可以打
I just came out with one
那剛才我出來一個
very serious patient
蠻嚴重的一個病人
After playing like this
這樣打了以後
he will stay for a while
他大概待一陣子以後
he has almost nothing to love
他幾乎是沒有所愛事
so this is very big
所以這個是非常大的
and make people feel
而且讓人要覺得
There are some developments to be excited about
有興奮的一些發展
is our response to inflammation
就是我們對發炎反應
The same goes for other diseases
其他疾病也是一樣
after knowing more
有更多了解之後
Then our medicine will be better
那我們的藥物也就會更好
good
好
Let's talk about the other two chronic inflammation
再講另外兩個慢性發炎
I don't know when
這個在不曉得什麼時候
Time Magazine above
Time Magazine上面
Especially when it comes to Information
特別講到Information
Talk about being a Secret Killer
講做Secret Killer
Just those psoriasis, sensitive
剛才那些乾癬、敏感
What we know is obviously that there is
我們的知道很明顯是有
Then know it's inflammation
然後知道是發炎
but in some cases
但有些情況下
We don't know there is inflammation
我們不知道有發炎
or unexpected inflammation
或者是沒想到發炎
be the cause of disease
會是造成的疾病的原因
It's serious in the end
到最後是蠻嚴重的
Here's what it says
這上面講說
Suppressing link between inflammation and heart attacks and cancer and Alzheimer's
Suppressing link between inflammation and heart attacks and cancer and Alzheimer's
Let me talk, I will talk about heart attack and cancer
我講一下,我會講 heart attack 跟 cancer
Y'all know Alzheimer's is dementia
你們都知道 Alzheimer's 是失智
is a serious problem
是很嚴重的問題
In fact, we now also know that he is such an important role as Information
事實上我們現在也知道他是 Information 這樣很重要的角色
There is information in the brain of the patient
病人裡面在腦部裡面是有 Information
And he ended up getting Alzheimer's symptoms
然後他最後是得到 Alzheimer's 症狀
I saw a news yesterday
昨天我看了一個消息
was published in the journal Nature Medicine
是在 Nature Medicine 雜誌裡面發表的
they had a team i no longer remember which school it was
他們有一個團隊,我不再記得是哪個學校的
There's a mouse, they're Genetic Modified mice
有個老鼠,他們是 Genetic Modified 老鼠
He started this automatically after their rat quarantine
他們老鼠隔離症之後開始這個就是他自動的
don't use any way
不要用怎麼樣的方式
He will automatically develop symptoms like Oscar
他就會自動會產生像奧斯坎美一樣的症狀
In addition, we know that Oskanme just said that it has something to do with the reaction to the speech
另外我們知道是在奧斯坎美剛剛說跟發言反應有關
In fact, two important
事實上是兩個重要的就是會造成奧斯坎美
not rely on them
並不是就是靠他們
But the important roles of these two battles are I-20, I-12, and I-23
但是這兩個戰重要角色就是I-20、I-12、I-23
It's about SWICE
就跟SWICE有關的
The team injected I-12, I-23 Anybody into this mouse
這個團隊就在這個老鼠裡面注射I-12、I-23的Anybody
like swice patients
就像SWICE病人一樣
As a result, one month later the mice were initially injected
結果一個月之後老鼠一開始就注射
After a month his symptoms were reduced by 30, 30, 40%
一個月之後他的症狀減低了30、30、40%
If there are some rats that already have symptoms, call him again
有一些已經有症狀的老鼠再給他打的話
He will also reduce the symptoms of Oscammy
他也奧斯坎美的症狀也會減低
So I believe this will be doing clinical trials soon
所以我相信這個很快會在做臨床的實驗
Because this medicine has been used for infection
因為這個藥已經拿來用在感染上面用了
So is it in Oscar now?
那現在是不是在奧斯坎美裡面
it will also be useful, it will be helpful
也會有用,也會有幫助
But we can actually expect to say whether there is
但是我們就可以事實上期待說是不是有
Is it an advance in this regard?
是不是在這方面的進檔
So it is said that it can treat Alzheimer's
所以造成說是能夠治療像Alzheimer的
Of course, there will be other advances in the future.
當然以後還有其他的進檔也可以
I just hope that after understanding this information
就是希望對這個information了解以後
able to have better medicines
能夠有更好的藥物
Then Alzheimer will not talk about it
那Alzheimer就不講了
Then talk about Heart Attack and Cancer
那就講Heart Attack and Cancer
So what I said earlier is what we usually see
那我前面講的是從比較通常看到的
of the disease, all of you are experienced
的病,各家各位都比較有經驗的
Then I will talk about it later, I hope everyone
那後面再講的是希望說是各位
is not affected
就是並沒有受到影響的
But this normal Colonial artery
但是這個正常的Colonial artery
This coronary artery
這個冠狀多脈
this young time
這個年輕的時候
We want our coronary arteries to look like this too
我們也希望我們的冠狀多脈都像這樣子
But gradually there will be some cases
但是慢慢的就會有些情況下
there will be some arteries on weekends
會有些動脈周末
I'm in the past
这些事我都是过去
In particular, the original lecture should be learned
原讲特别要学一下
But it is good to keep Azure Scrooge
但是还是养Azure Scrooge是好的
Then you see its blood vessels become narrow
然后你看它的血管就变成窄了
At this time, if there is Block Cloud
这个时候如果有Block Cloud的时候
it doesn't work at all
它就完全不通了
At this time, because of the coronavirus, buying more is
这个时候因为冠状多买是
need blood transfusion
要输血跟养气
And Nutrition to the cells of the heart
还有Nutrition到心脏的细胞
Therefore, if the blood vessels cannot be blocked
所以血管一不能不通的话
These blood vessels will die
这些血管都会死掉
At the end is a Heart Attack
最后就是一个Heart Attack
This definition is because
这个定义就是因为
Substances of Fat and Cholesterol
脂肪和胆固醇的物质
Scores in vessel B which lead to vessel imprinting
成绩在血管B而导致血管印化
so it's normal
所以这是正常的
And here's Azure Scrooge
而这边有Azure Scrooge
It's called a plaque and it seems to be
这叫做斑块好像是
About 1000 people, there are about 7 people
大概是1000个里面大概是7个人
But this is the whole population
但這個是全部的population
Of course it will be the most when you are older
在年紀大的話當然就會比最多了
In the U.S. there are approximately 5 million
在美國大概有將近500萬
get this arteriosclerosis
得到這個動脈硬化
What about the symptoms?
那症狀呢
words in the heart
在心臟的話
dear words
是親的話
there will be pain in the heart and feet
會有心腳痛
words in that
那中的話
fatal myocardial infarction
有致命性的心肌梗塞
brain words
腦部的話
Feel dizzy and headache when kissing
親的時候會感到頭暈頭痛
when the face is heavy
臉重的時候
there will be a stroke of haste
會有急心的中風
When the blood vessels in the feet
那腳部的血管的時候
some
有些
ischemic necrosis of lower extremities
下肢的缺血壞死
that sometimes have to
那有時候不得不
congealing
結脂
then you can save your life
然後才能保住性命
why?
原因呢
the reason is
原因呢就是
of course
當然是
the disease just mentioned
剛才講的疾病
almost always some
幾乎都是有些
family death
家族病死
would be more stupid
會更愚蠢
This is no exception
這個也是不例外
that time of aging
那老化的時候
This heart is easier to harden
這個心臟比較容易硬化
What's more, high blood pressure
那另外呢就是高血壓
also a big reason
也是一個大的原因
the diabetic patient
那彈尿病的病人
easier to get
比較容易得到
Can be used until hardened
可以使用到硬化
external factors
外在的因素
If it is a film and television with a bold process
如果是高胆过程的影视
I think you should be very clear
我想各位应该很清楚
Or smoking will harden this anime too
或者吸烟也会造成这个动漫硬化
The reason is what is its mechanism?
原因是它的机制是怎么样的呢
If collesterol is high
如果是collesterol高的时候
especially low density
尤其是low density
A wave of protein
一波protein
It will settle down in the school tube
它会在学管里面沉淀下来
it will be modified
它会被modify
modify is actually oxidized
modify事实上是被oxidized
These oxidized LDA
这些oxidized LDA
will be eaten by megalithic cells or aggregated cells
会被巨石细胞或是集状细胞吃进去
These produce an inflammatory response
这些产生发炎反应
The entire school tube has some inflammation around the week
整个学管在周附近有些发炎反应
And the final result is anime hardening
而到最后结果就是动漫硬化
This is a beautiful cartoon
這個是很漂亮的一個卡通
write slightly more clearly
寫得稍微更清楚一點
this is LDL it will come in
這是LDL它會進來
Cholesterol
Colesterol
then it gets oxidized
然後它會得氧化
how is it
它怎麼樣呢?
It will activate the B cells of this blood vessel
會讓它這個血管的B的細胞活化
Then Molicyte will come in
然後Molicyte就會進來
After coming in, it will clear Modified LDL
進來之後它會清除Modified LDL
Oxidl LDL
Oxidl LDL
Then it ends up being all in
然後它最後變成全部在裡面
We are called Formcell
我們叫做Formcell
This is also easier to activate
這個也是比較容易被活化
And it secretes some substances that cause inflammation
而它會分泌一些造成發炎的一些物質
So here it becomes and these Colesterols are there
所以這邊就變成又有這些Colesterol在那裡
another inflammatory reaction
又有發炎反應
This is blood going on here
這個是血液在這邊進行
this is a blood vessel
這個是血管
Here are blood vessels B
這邊都是血管B
So the word here is the so-called plaque
所以這邊的話就是所謂的斑塊
At the same time, this inflammatory response will make the
同時這個發炎反應會讓這邊的
muscle cells proliferate
肌肉細胞有增值
Then it will bury and come to this place
然後它會埋會到這個地方來
So blood vessels are getting thicker and thicker
所以血管幣越來越厚
less and less blood vessels
血管的通道越來越少
Getting smaller and smaller
越來越小
So it can be seen here
所以這邊的話可以看得出來
That's where the plaque is created
就是在這裡就產生斑塊的地方
muscle cells here
這邊有肌肉細胞
these are cells
這些是細胞
You can see the words here
可以看到這邊的話
here is getting thicker
這邊是越來越厚
But here the coins of the blood vessels of the cells
但這邊這個細胞血管的幣
is getting thinner
是越來越薄
If compared with the original
跟原來比較起來的話
The port is getting smaller and smaller
通口越來越小
If there's an inflammatory reaction here, it's going to be a problem.
這邊如果發炎反應會造成一個問題
that's what's causing this side
就是它會造成這邊的
will affect the injury here
會影響到這邊受傷
So many inflammatory reactions will be linked with injury
所以很多發炎反應跟injury都會連在一起
Here, in this case, when there is injury
這邊在這個情況下有injury的時候
It's like saying this is when we usually bleed
這邊就像說是平常我們出血的時候
it has solidified
它有凝固
like i just said it was the one
就像我剛講說是那個
There will be bleeding when the wound will come in the school version
傷口的時候會有出血會學校版進來
Of course it freezes, and it's the same here
當然凝固,這邊也是一樣
Here's the last thrombus
這邊最後產生血栓
After a thrombus occurs, this side will not pass through.
產生血栓以後這邊就不通了
Then this is what causes HotelTab
然後這就是造成HotelTab
The same is for us to know and say yes
那同樣的就是要我們知道說是
This arteriosclerosis is related to inflammation
這個動脈硬化跟發炎有關
So many companies began to study to see if inflammation
所以很多公司就開始研究看發炎
See if the inflammatory drug can treat this heart disease
看發炎藥物,是否能夠治療這個心臟病
Many of these children in the face to face tree
這些很多在face to face tree的child
Let me give you two examples
比如說講兩個例子好了
The first one is that this is anti-oxidation of LDA
第一個是這個是抗LDA的氧化
I just mentioned that LDA is oxidized first
我剛提到說是LDA先氧化
and then cause this inflammatory response
然後再會造成這個發炎反應
If it can prevent it from oxidizing
如果說能夠把它不讓它氧化的話
maybe this helps
也許對這有幫助
That's more to do with inflammation
那跟發炎反應更有關係就是
This is a kind of regionalized silver, this is Kinokain
這個是一種就是區化銀子,這是Kinokain
So this company is making this Kinokain not work
所以這個公司就是讓這個Kinokain不作用
And this monocyte will not have
而這個單核細胞也不會有
It will not enter the study of learning, nor will it enter this class
也不會進到學習的學習,也不會進到這個班塊裡面
So this is still in the second issue
所以這是現在還在第二期中
The last paragraph is the relationship with Cancer
最後一段就是跟Cancer的關係
I think this must be
我想這個一定是
Fort de la Léz cancer is now our
Fort de la Léz cancer是現在我們對
is the most difficult
就是最比較不容易
a disease of the handle
handle的一個疾病
Also most in need of research development
也最需要研究上的發展
and then hope to get a well-developed drug
然後希望能得到發展好的藥物
This Cancer is indeed
這個Cancer確實是
In the past many years, I did not think of the relationship with Information
過去多年來並沒有想到跟Information的關係
But now, you look at the textbook
但現在呢,你去看教科書上面
clearly written
寫得很清楚就是
That is, Information is a very important role of the website.
就是Information是站非常大的一個角色
play a very big role
做非常大的一個角色
there are two points
那有兩點
one is in that
一個是在那個
In case of chronic inflammation
慢性發炎的情況下
Cancel will develop
Cancell會發展出來
For example H.Pylo-E
比如說H.Pylo-E
Helicopter-Pylo-E inside the stomach
Helicopter-Pylo-E在胃裡面
This can cause gastritis
這個會造成胃炎
But if it is said that this treatment is not removed
但是如果說是沒有把這處理除掉
Over time, some people
久而久之有些人裡面
Among many people, he will know about gastric cancer
不少數人裡面他會知道胃癌
That's another Inflammatory Bowel Disease
那另外是Infammatory Bowel Disease
Just inside the Colon
就在Colon裡面
it will have long term information
它會有長期的資訊
This is in a small number of patients
這個在少數病人裡面
It will end up with Colon Rectocancin
它最後會有Colon Rectocancin
Then in Taiwan, it is more often Hepatitis
然後在台灣比較多是Heptitis
Hepatitis B or C
就是肝病毒B型或C型
This causes viral infection
這個造成病毒感染
followed by an inflammatory response
然後造成發炎反應
when it comes to the end
那到最後期的時候
Some patients develop hepatitis and liver cancer
有些病人就會產生變成肝炎肝癌
It's an inflammatory reaction
這都是在發炎反應
after becoming a chronic inflammatory reaction
就是變成慢性的發炎反應之後
In some cases it can also cause CANS
有一些情況下還會造成CANS
So this is the first example of the relationship between inflammation and CANS
所以這是發炎跟CANS的關係的第一個
If you draw it here, you will be a good boy.
那這邊畫出來就是一個好童就是
Here is an inflammatory reaction
這邊是發炎反應
That should be a normal cell
那本來是應該正常細胞
it turns into cancer cells
它會變成癌細胞
That's why it's like this in detail
那詳細形形就是為什麼會這樣子
not entirely clear
並不完全清楚
But what we know is that these inflammatory reactions
但是知道的就是這些發炎反應的
some inflammatory factors
有些發炎因子
Can cause some genetic changes in this normal cell
能夠造成這個正常細胞一些基因的改變
For example mutation
比如說mutation
After the mutation is generated
產生mutation之後
This cell becomes a cancer cell
它這張細胞就變成癌細胞了
The other relationship with the inflammatory response is
那另外跟發炎反應的關係是
After becoming a cancer cell
變成癌細胞之後
Surrounding cancer cells is an inflamed
癌細胞的周遭是一個發炎的
is an inflamed
是一個發炎的
is a response to inflammation inside
是一個在裡面發炎的一個反應
How does that cause an inflammatory reaction?
那怎麼樣造成發炎的反應
not entirely clear
並不完全清楚
But of course cancer cells secrete a lot of
但是當然癌細胞它會分泌不少的
Even what I just said was Sedkar
甚至剛才講的就是賽德卡
Chimocha will be secreted
奇摩卡它都會分泌出來
so it attracts these
因此它會吸引到這些
these inflammatory reactions
這些發炎反應
Some people say that cancer is like an injury that cannot be cured
那有人说是cancer就像是一个没有办法治好的一个injury
So the host is always thinking about repairing it
那因此在host就是一直在想repair它
repair it is the reaction of pronunciation around here
repair它这附近都是发音的反应
Then we knew about cancer in the past
那过去我们知道cancer的话
It is continuing to reproduce in it
它是继续继续在里面繁殖
and its cells are less likely to die
而且它的细胞比较不容易死亡
so let's just say
所以我们就说过去
let's just talk
我们就说过去
Cells are less likely to die
细胞比较不容易死亡
Then cancer it needs blood vessels
然后cancer它需要血管
to supply it with oxygen
才能供应它的氧气
or its nutrient
或是它的nutrient
Then it also knows how to
那它也知道怎么样能够
make new blood vessels
制造新的血管
then its immune system
然后它免疫系统
Society sees cancer cells
社会看到cancer的细胞
and want to remove it
而想把它去除掉
But cancer cells also know what to look like
但是cancer细胞也知道怎么样子
Evade elimination by immune cells
躲避免疫细胞的清除
But now we know that when you put in the persistent chronic inflammation
但是現在我們知道,再把持續的慢性發炎放進去
Right around this Cancel, it has been chronically inflamed
就在這Cancel的周遭,它是一直有慢性的發炎
And this chronic inflammation, as mentioned just now, it will cause the gene to have mutation
而這個慢性的發炎,就剛才已經提到過,它會基因,讓基因有Mutation
At the same time, it will promote the proliferation of this cancer cell just now
同時它會促進這個,剛才這個癌症細胞的增生
It promotes the formation of blood vessels
它是促進血管的形生
And then finally, hepatitis, and finally that cancer cell washes into nearby cells
然後最後,肝炎,最後那個癌細胞會清洗到附近的細胞
In the end, it will spread, the factors of these inflammatory reactions
最後會做蔓延,那這些發炎的反應的因子
or its cells will facilitate this process
或者它的細胞都會促進這方面的過程
So this is a great idea that inflammation leads to cancer, now a thought
所以這個是發炎反應引導癌症發生的一個大賴的,現在的一個想法
If this is the case, then see medicine, can inflammation medicine be useful in treating cancer?
那既然這樣的話,那看藥,發炎藥是不是能在看癌上面能夠有用呢?
This is indeed the case, it is IceBrain, the medicine we use very often
確實是這樣子,就是IceBrain,我們非常經常用的藥
we know it looks inflammatory
我們知道它是看發炎的
Therefore, in a clinical trial
因此在一個臨床實驗上
visible
可以看到的
we know we probably
我們知道我們大概
Should be after the age of 50
應該是50歲之後
can eat spring
是可以吃spring
otherwise eat a small amount
不然吃少量
So some people have eaten spring
所以有些人已經吃了spring
I have eaten it for more than 20 years
吃了20多年了
It plays a role in the risk of colorectal cancer
它在產生大腸癌的機率
It is indeed less than no food
確實是比沒有吃的少了
30% 40%
30% 40%
So this is a
所以這個是一個
Proved to be inflamed on coffee
證明說是對咖啡上看發炎
can be slightly reduced
是可以稍微減低
cancer cancer
得癌症的癌症的
A Proof of the Rate of Interest
利激率的一種證明
Of course more research is needed
當然還是需要更多的研究
work to learn more about this
工作才能夠把這多了解一下
Also this is right
另外這個是對
prostaglandins
前列腺素
Looks like inflammation medicine
看來的看發炎藥
In fact it's endosterol
事實上是內蠱醇
These two words are more commonly used
這兩個的話是比較常用的
from arthritis
是自關節炎
for pain
是疼痛用的
It is now clinically proven
那現在在臨床上也證明
In fact, it is helpful in the treatment of cancer
事實上是對治療癌症適合有幫助的
I think this is the last one
我想這是最後一張了
Finally, I would like to thank the postdoctoral students in the laboratory
那我最後要謝謝實驗室的博士後海學生
This is the first preparation
這個是最先是準備
It is the material I gave to the research institute of National Taiwan University
是我給在臺大研究所的材料
For this popular science speech
為了這科普演講
Please help me change it to a more popular word
請他們幫我改成比較大眾的話
Then the most important thing is to put Chinese in
然後最重要是把中文放進來
Because in the United States for many years
因為在美國多年
So if I speak Chinese, I need someone else to translate for me.
所以中文的話就需要靠別人幫我翻譯
then thank them
那謝謝他們
Thank you for your attention
謝謝各位的 attention
Thanks
謝謝
we are very grateful
我們很謝謝
And Liu Shouchang went from a good inflammatory reaction to a bad inflammatory reaction
而且柳首長從好的發炎反應到壞的發炎反應
Even Bad Inflammation Causes Common Diseases in Our Humans
甚至壞的發炎反應引起我們人類常見的疾病
we often talk
我們常常講說
What are the two most important causes of death in Taiwan?
台灣最重要的兩大死因是什麼
The number one cause of death is cancer
第一大死因就是癌症
The second leading cause of death is heart disease and stroke
第二大死因心臟病還有腦中風
So in fact we used to think that
所以實際上我們以前常常認為說
These things like cancer cardiovascular disease
這些像癌症心臟血管疾病的東西
Nothing to do with inflammation
都跟發炎沒有關
Now after we listened to Chief Liu's speech today
現在我們今天聽了這個柳首長的演講以後
I know that these common human diseases
知道說原來這些人類常見的疾病
A very important cause of death is also related to inflammation
很重要的死因也都是跟發炎有關
We thank Chief Liu for his speech
我們謝謝柳首長的演講
Now we follow net profit
現在我們按照網利
time for some Q&A
有一些Q&A的時間
everyone can ask
大家可以發問
Then we will ask Chief Liu to answer with you
然後我們再請柳首長跟大家來回答
OK
好不好
is there anything please
有沒有什麼來請
ask questions
各位要問問題
Please use the microphone and introduce yourself
請用麥克風還有介紹一下你自己
okay thank you
好不好 謝謝
Hello, Mr. Liu
柳首長你好
Institute of Medical Informatics, Taipei Medical University
台北醫學大學醫學資訊研究所
One problem is that I didn't seem to specifically mention it just now.
一個問題是剛剛好像沒有特別講到說
It is also related to speech
也是跟發言凡有關
But it's an autoimmune disease
但是是自體免疫的疾病
So derived from this
所以由這個衍生
Autoimmunity should always be irregular
自體免疫應該是一直不定期的
There have been some informational speeches somewhere in the
一直在某些地方有一些資訊發言在
Will he be related to the Egyptian government because of this?
那他跟埃政會不會也因此導致會有關聯
Thanks
謝謝
Okay, thank you
好,謝謝
Yes, autoimmunity was a very important one at the time
對,自身免疫當時非常重要的一個
is the immune system
就是免疫系統
some are too strong
有些等於是過強了
Then he shouldn't be affected
那他就是不應該影響到的
For example, to our own cells
比如說是對我們自己的細胞
usually should not have immunity
平常是不應該有免疫力
but there is no control
但是就是沒有控制
So in the case of 4
所以說是4條的情況下
to ourselves
對我們自己產生的
own cells generate immunity
自己的細胞產生免疫力
Of course this is
那這個當然也是
In addition to responding to the speech
除了也是跟發言反應
He is also closely related
跟他也是息息相關
Then this one is also immune
那這個也是這免疫的
As for the relationship with the sea
那至於跟海參與關係
As far as I know it's not that obvious
據我知道並不是那麼明顯
some have , in fact there are
有些有,事實上是有
in fact there is
事實上是有
then i have to tell
那我必須要講一下
good question you said
你說很好的問題
For example, hand cancer, liver cancer
比如說是手癌疾肝癌
I don't see it so far
目前看出來並沒有意想到
that cancer
那個癌疾
For example, liver cancer is an inflammation of the skin
譬如說肝癌是皮膚的發炎反應
But it did not increase the incentives for skin cancer
但是它並沒有讓皮膚的癌疾的激勵會增加
So it's not exactly one-to-one
所以並不是完全是一對一的
So what about autoimmunity?
那至於說是自身免疫的話
Some autoimmunity does not mean more cancer
有些自身免疫並不是說是會多的癌疾
but some words are
但是有些的話是有
For example, there is a thing called Polymycitis
譬如說是有個叫做Polymycitis
So an autoimmune response in the muscles
所以肌肉的自身免疫的一種反應
that inside
那這個裡面的
The motivation of that cancer is very high
那個癌疾的激勵滿高的
right
對
I will teach you a few steps to solve it
我教你們幾步要沒有解決
just go ahead and answer your questions
就繼續回答你的問題
come on this side
來,這一邊
ask the director
請教所長
Director just mentioned about liver gland
剛所長有提到關於肝腺
What is the difference between hepatic gland and odorous dermatitis
肝腺跟異味性皮膚炎有什麼差異
Thanks
謝謝
these two are different
這兩個是不一樣的
One is the liver gland is the love is
一個是肝腺是所愛是
The odor is A.Towelge-Metallis
異味性是A.Towelge-Metallis
These are two different
這個是兩種不同的
completely different disease
完全不同的疾病
and it can be distinguished
而且是可以分得出來的
Slicing is usually less needed
通常不太需要切片
you can see
就可以看得出來
That is to look at its shape on the one hand
那就是一方面看它的形狀
So called morphology
所以叫mophology
As for its cause
至於它的變因的話
have to be the same
也不得不太一樣
that's clean
那乾淨就是
Odor allergic dermatitis
異味性過敏皮膚炎的話
I just told you
是跟剛講過
With that B.M.
跟那個B.M.
related to asthma
跟氣喘比較有關係
What about immunity
那在免疫上面的話
Let's just say this with
我們就說這個跟
With that D2 TH2
跟那個D2型的TH2
T cells
就是T細胞
Type II related
第二型有關的
What about liver cancer
那肝癌的話
it is now
它是現在
In the past we thought it was TH50,000
過去我們認為它是TH5萬
Type I
第一型
But now it is clear that it is
但現在比較清楚是它是
another one
另外一個
The other one talks more and more
另外一個就越講越比較
specialized
專業化了
TH7T related
TH7T有關
Yes these two are different mechanisms
是這兩個是不同的機制
Affecting
影響的
different etiologies
不同的病因
right
對
Just mentioned that liver cancer
剛剛提到說那個肝癌
It is good for liver cancer
對肝癌有好處的是
what moisturizing lotion and that steroid
什麼保濕乳液跟那個類固醇
dermatitis that signifies
那意味性皮膚炎
Is it also necessary to use quality
是不是也需要用質量
Yes, just a few medicines
對就是剛剛幾個藥
almost all can be used
幾乎都可以用
right
對
That is to say, on liver cancer
就是說在肝癌上面
use
用的
especially if internal alcohol
尤其是內部醇的話
is in
是在
emblematic dermatitis
意味性皮膚炎
is available
是可以用
Then what
然後呢
Illuminated
照光
The same goes for ultraviolet light
照紫外線光也是一樣
It can be used for dermatitis and liver cancer
就是對皮膚炎跟肝癌都可以用
That's a pity that these
那可惜的是這些
These so-called Biotic
這些後來講的所謂的Biotic
that is currently in
那目前在
on allergic dermatitis
在過敏皮膚炎上面
not yet
還沒有
no other medicine
還沒對方的藥
So progress on clean is much faster than that
所以在乾淨上面的進步比那個快很多
Thanks
謝謝
In principle, I am an ordinary citizen
原則碼我是一般的民眾
i want to ask a question
我想請教一個問題
We just mentioned this term from the inflammation industry
我們剛剛提到發炎產業的這個名詞
Then the general treatment with drugs
那麼一般用藥物治療
Inflammation is a principle code anti-hours
就是發炎是有原則碼抗時數
Its ties to this inflamed industry
它這個發炎產業的關係
What Actually Affects Inflammatory Industry Relationships
其實有什麼影響到發炎產業的關係
This school question asks if you are
這個學校的問題問你是不是這樣
This is what we talk about to see vitamins
這是我們講個看生素
usually a bacterial infection
通常是看有細菌感染
shall we use it again
我們再用對不對
So the first one is
所以第一個就是
If there is a bacterial infection
如果有細菌感染之後
Look at the antibiotics to get rid of the bacteria
你先看生素把這細菌去掉
Of course there were bacteria next.
那當然是接下來本來有細菌的
bacteria can cause
細菌可以造成
Initiation reaction
發源反應
Since you don't have bacteria
那你既然沒有器菌的話
There will be no reaction at the source
就發源反應就沒有了
so here's an idea
所以這是一個想法
This is what we really see as numbers
這是我們真正的看成數
but
但是
in fact
事實上
We now know a lot about numbers
我們現在知道很多看成數
It has the effect of looking at the origin
它有看發源的作用
it depends on the role of origin
它看發源的作用
so i don't want you guys
所以我想不要各位
Do you have
有沒有
Is it Echme please wait
是不是Echme 請等等
that that
那那個
it's the usual way
這很通常的方法
slightly more serious
比較稍微嚴重的時候
Is to use antibiotics
是用antibiotics
use that as a number
用那個看成數
In fact it works
事實上它用的作用
Not exactly because it's bacterial drying
並不完全是因為它是細菌乾燥
It actually has bacteria
它事實上細菌是有
Will cause
會造成
Echme
Echme
But its function is
但是它的功能是
it looks at origin
它看發源
So there are a lot of viewers
所以有不少的看人數
There is a function to see the origin
有看發源的功能
So these two reasons
所以這兩個原因
is itself
就是它本身
There is a function to see the origin
有看發源的功能
I think that explains your problem
我想是不是解釋了你的問題
I'm sorry, sir, I'll ask you a little more.
不好意思 所長再請教一點
Just now you said dry and salty is for life
剛剛你說乾鹹是一輩子的
no way to eat fish
沒有辦法吃魚
Is there any way to eat fish with the smelly skin?
那異味性皮膚也有沒有辦法吃魚
Because now is the picture just drawn
因為現在就是剛剛那個圖畫出來
So it's okay, maybe 60 to 70% of children
所以是還好大概是百分之六七十的小孩子
By the age of ten or so, there will be no
到了差不多到十歲左右就沒有
sometimes come out later
有時候後來才會再出來
But one time it will get lighter and lighter
但是是一次會越來越輕
in the end not even
到最後甚至就沒有
So it's more dry and salty than long-term
所以那倒是乾鹹比較是長期性的
Sixty to seventy percent of odorous skin
異味性皮膚也百分之六七十
will not continue the opportunity
是不會繼續機會下去
It's gone when you reach adulthood
就是到成年的時候就會沒有了
But my child is already in his twenties and thirties
可是我的孩子已經二三十歲
That's a pity to be in those 30s again
那就是可惜又是在那三十歲的
So how can this be said to be questioned?
那這個要怎麼樣能夠說把它質疑
Then questioning is like asking dry salty
那就質疑就像跟乾鹹一樣還繼續要
take medicine, keep taking medicine
用藥了,繼續用藥
That is, so far, most of them are not compatible with that, and that is lighting
那就是當目前為止,大部分是用類不成跟那個,跟那個就是照光
Illuminated
照光
So there is a chance that odorous dermatitis can be cured
所以異味性皮膚炎有機會可以治癒了
So it's me, it's me
所以實在是我,實在是我
Pharmaceutical companies in this area usually do not do much because most of the children have
這方面的藥廠通常比較不太做是因為大部分是小孩子有
Then also know that they will be gone after a while
然後也知道他們隔一陣子就會沒有
So it's a little bit more difficult for him to do clinical work in the children's department, yes.
所以他在小孩子的,對,都做臨床的事業也比較困難一點
So usually, the one here usually cooks a lot more than dry and salty stir-fry
所以通常,通常那個這邊做的比乾鹹炒很多
But I believe so, now but I can mention that
但是我相信也是,現在但是我可以提一下就是
There is still gallbladder cleansing, the amine tire IGE just mentioned
淨膽還是有,剛剛講的胺胎IGE
In fact, it is helpful for dermatitis, and it can be used
事實上在皮膚炎上面是有幫助,是可以用
So odorous dermatitis will fade with age
所以說異味性皮膚炎會隨著年齡越來越淡化
It's different, it's when I was a kid, when I was a kid
不一樣,就是在小孩子的時候,小孩子的時候
But grown-ups still sometimes, sometimes
但是大人還是有的時候,有時候就會有
I think there will always be
覺得就會一直會有
Yes, not necessarily clear
對 不一定會清
not necessarily clear
不一定會清
Thanks
謝謝
Thank you for sharing
謝謝所長的分享
what you just said
剛剛說的你說
50 years old or R10P person
50歲或是R10P人
Will reduce the suspicious rate of colorectal cancer
會減少大腸癌的疑分率
That said, after colorectal cancer surgery
那說大腸癌手術後
eat R10P people
吃R10P人
Will it reduce hair care rate
會不會降低護髮率
I don't know if there is any data here
這邊的數據我不曉得有沒有
I don't know if there is
不曉得有沒有
yes it is still possible
是還是有可能性
but i want aesthrin to eat
但是我想Aesthrin吃
i want to be there
我想在那個
heart attack by that bath
在那個浴旁心臟病
It's obvious from the top of the heavy madness
跟重瘋的上面是很明顯的
So I also say this reason
所以我也說這個原因
That's why I think it's edible
也是這個原因我覺得是可以吃
low dose
就是低劑量的
in that
在那個
The words above cancer
cancer上面的話
Not saying it's 100 percent, it's just lowering the force.
並不是說是百分之百 它只是降低力卸而已
That data is quite obvious
那那個數據是蠻明顯的
Only in the case of this complex flowering
只是在這種復花的情況下
I don't think there's any data on this right now
我想目前並沒有這方面的數據
I knew it
我就知道
ask the director
請教一下所長
in terms of allergies
在過敏方面
Is there any way for that IG part
那個IG的部分有沒有什麼方式
Like exercising or avoiding drugs
譬如說運動或是不要用藥物的方式
You can increase the possibility of IG
可以去增加IG的可能性
This is the birth of this IG
就是這個IG的產生
I guess there's always no downside in sports
我想運動當中總是沒有壞處
as long as you don't get hurt
只要不受傷的話
but on sensitive
但是在敏感上面的話
haven't said yes yet
還沒有說是
But movement is, on the one hand, e.g.
但運動一方面是譬如說是
if you are overweight
如果是你是過重
Sometimes asthma is related to OBCT
有的時候氣喘是跟OBCT也是有關係的
So exercise less
所以運動的話減少
is to reduce it
就是讓其中減低了減輕
These indirect effects on health
這些間接的影響到對身體好
this should help
這個應該是會有幫助
But for the generation of this IG
但是對於這個IG的產生
These inflammatory mechanisms are sensitive to this
這些發炎對這個敏感的機制
As far as I know it doesn't say it will decrease
據我知道並沒有說是會減少
yes
是
right
對
sultan ask
蘇丹請教一下
Just now when you mentioned the allergic reaction
剛剛您在提到過敏反應的時候
mast cells
有提到肥大細胞
Does this mast cell mean fat cell?
這個肥大細胞是不是指的是肥胖細胞
Then it's inflammation and obesity
那它就是發炎跟肥胖
with the one you just mentioned
跟您剛剛所提到的那個
between cardiovascular disease and cancer
就是心血管疾病跟癌症之間
What is its cause and effect relationship?
它的因果關係是怎麼樣的
Thanks
謝謝
That is not this mast cell is Massal
那個不是這個肥大細胞是Massal
you said fat
是你說肥胖
In fact, I'm obese, I think you're obese
事實上肥胖我就我想你講的肥胖
may refer to fat cells
可能是指脂肪細胞
And the point gill
而地步腮
those are two different
那是兩個不一樣的
obesity
肥胖
It is mast cell, it is Mass cell
就是肥大細胞,就是Mass cell
Then it is quite a unique cell
然後它是蠻獨特的一個細胞
It really has something to do with that sensitivity
真的就是跟那個敏感很有關係的
It is what makes the inside of our human body
它就是造成那個我們人體裡面
Probably this cell will produce Histamine
大概就是這個細胞會產生Histamine
I know this Nutriphia also produces
我知道這個Nutriphia也產生
but so far
但是目前為止
Probably what the textbook said is Histamine
大概教科書上面講的就是Histamine的話
All Mass cells are produced by mast cells
都是Mass cell就是肥大細胞產生的
But this mast cell
但是這個肥大細胞
It is actually in other diseases
就是實在在其他的疾病裡面
There will be, there will be, and there will be
也有,也會有,也會有作用
even in cancer
甚至在cancer裡面
Mass cell also does research
Mass cell也做研究
Mass cell has also been researched in the generation of cancer
Mass cell在cancer的產生裡面也有做研究的
Also found that Mass cell will be effective
也發現Mass cell會有功
Will contribute to the generation of cancer
會contribute到cancer的產生
So it does a lot
所以它的作用是蠻多的
But it is more researched
但是它是比較研究比較多的
is a sensitive reaction
是敏感反應
Sensitive reactions are very many
敏感反應是非常多的
very obvious function
非常明顯的一種功能
later
後面
here first
這邊先好了
Usually when we go to see a doctor
一般我們身邊去看醫生的時候
The doctor will tell you to take some anti-inflammatory drugs
醫生都會說給你吃點消炎藥
According to ordinary people, the practice of turning the wheel
那所轉輪功就一般民眾講
So are anti-inflammatory drugs antibiotics or
所以消炎藥到底是抗生素還是
still sweating
還是汗濃濃
Let the common people understand your
讓一般人了解你的
The confusion is which one is called an anti-inflammatory drug
搞混的是哪一種叫消炎藥
I don't have that kind of experience
我倒沒有這種經驗
so we know
所以我們曉得是
Speaking of anti-inflammatory drugs
講的放消炎藥
Anti-inflammatory drugs are here
消炎藥是這邊是指
What kind of say an example is what
什麼樣的比如說一個例子是什麼
as we just said
像剛才我們講的
is undaefermetary medicine
就是undaefermetary藥
there are some
那有一些
especially in taiwan
尤其在台灣
many people say
很多人都說
There are some
有一些
inflammatory reactions are some
發炎的反應就是一些
this anti-inflammatory drug
這一個消炎藥
that's something like
那有一些像是
Aspirin
Aspirin
or something like
或者是有一些像是
to some of these
對 一些這些
Some anti-inflammatory drugs like steroids
會類固醇類的一些消炎的藥物
These are the ones that are often opened in China.
那這一些是一般在國內常常會開
there is such a medicine
有這樣的藥
Now the question just now is
那現在剛才的問題就是說
Are these anti-inflammatory drugs?
到底這些消炎藥是不是
Since it's inflammation, it's not good
既然是發炎是不太好
Then there will be all kinds of inflammation
然後會有引起各式的發炎
So should we take some anti-inflammatory drugs?
那我們是不是該吃一些發炎的藥物呢
anti-inflammatory drugs
抗發炎的藥物
Like Aspirin is a particle
像是Aspirin 就是一個粒子
Particles like Tylenol
像Tylenol的粒子
Tylenol is an inflammatory
對 Tylenol是一個發炎
is anti-inflammatory
是抗發炎的
Right, so that's probably a
對不對 所以那個大概是一個
Then there shouldn't be any harm in that.
那這個應該是沒有壞處了
should be no harm
應該是沒有壞處
Of course the most effective anti-inflammation is the inner bone hip
那當然是最有效的抗發炎是內骨臀
You can still eat when necessary
必要的時候還是可以吃
For that fork, we usually
那叉的話我們是通常
As long as there is no residual error
只要不殘糾差的話
actually helps
事實上是有幫助 對
But if you look at the speech, these words
但是如果說你這看發言的事,這些的話
I think it depends on what kind of disease it is.
我想是看是什麼樣的病就是了
yes what kind of disease
對,什麼樣的病
If it is pain in these joints
如果說是疼痛這些關節言
If talking about watching speeches
如果說講的是看發言的話
Probably this Ib Profit
大概是這個Ib Profit這些
or memory
或是內骨存
or Tylenol
或是Tylenol
There seems to be a problem behind that
那後面好像有問題
there is a problem with this
這方面有問題
Please ask me for a long time
長載請教一下
Current use of allergy medications
目前在使用過敏的藥物方面
Which one works better
哪一個的成效比較好
As for the extent of his side effects
至於他的副作用又到什麼程度
Is there any use of this aspect in traditional Chinese medicine?
那在中藥方面有沒有這一方面的使用
Thanks
謝謝
When you say allergic, you mean like Bn
你說過敏是指比如Bn
Yes, Bn's words
對,Bn的話
Bn is still Antihistimum so far
Bn目前為止還是Antihistimum
It is the main medicine
是主業主藥的
But if necessary, use internal bone storage
但是必要的話只好用內骨存
But if it is slight, most Anti-Hismis can be
但輕微的話大部分Anti-Hismis是可以
As for, for example, Anti-IG
至於譬如像Anti-IG的話
I think it should be very useful
我是覺得應該是非常有用的
But it's a bit like killing a chicken with a bull's knife
但是有點像殺雞用牛刀的感覺
of course something
當然有些事
especially you are very very sad
尤其是你是非常非常難過
is edible
是可以吃
But then it becomes the so-called off-level
但是那就變成所謂的off-level
Because the U.S. Department of Health
因為美國的衛生署
Didn't say it was proof
並沒有說是proof
This is the thing to avoid smoking
就是這東西來當避煙用
It is Azema
它是Azema
But Moderny-Civill
而就是Moderny-Civill
but in the US
但在美國
Used in non-Moderny-Civill-Azema
用在不是Moderny-Civill-Azema
I think there are still many people using
我想還是有不少人在用
but if it is slight
但是如果是輕微的話
if it's not that serious
不是那麼嚴重的話
I don't think you need to use this
我想就不需要用到這個
use this
用到這個
It is because of those biological
就是因為那些biological
is quite expensive
是相當貴的
The annual fee is in US dollars
一年的費用都是美金的
Ten thousand and twenty thousand
上一萬兩萬
I have to say that I just mentioned a lot of scientific names and company names
我必須講一下 我剛才講了很多學名還有公司的名字
I really have no conflict
我實在是沒有conflict
No
沒有
I don't have that stock
我沒有那個stock
Neither do I. I'm not and I'm not the one who invented it.
我也沒有 我不也不是發明的人
There are many types of allergies
過敏的藥物有很多種
some are cheap and some are expensive
那有一些是很便宜的 有一些是很貴的
A tribute to some creatures like the ones just mentioned
像剛才講的這一些生物致敬
anti-IgE antibodies
就是抗IgE的抗體
actually
實際上
Insufficient not very severe symptoms of severe asthma
不足的不是很嚴重 很嚴重的氣喘的症狀
But to use that medicine
而要用那種藥的話
as we say
就像我們所講的
Is it worth it to spend a lot of money?
就花很多的錢 那值不值得這樣去做呢
Of course, the health insurance will not be given based on Taiwan's history.
那當然健保也就不會給給以臺灣的歷史上來看
Because your disease is not serious enough to need this drug
因為你的病還沒有嚴重到需要用到這種藥
is a general allergic reaction
是一般過敏反應
Or anti-organism drugs, etc.
還是抗組織案等等的這一些藥物
General health insurance will give
一般健保會給給
but if to
但是如果到
bio tribute section
生物致敬的部分
In the case of Taiwan's health insurance, the possibility of giving is probably very low
以臺灣健保的情況下 大概給給的可能性很低
unless it's serious like
除非是很嚴重的 像是
Teresa Teng's severe asthma
鄧麗君這種嚴重的氣喘
Then this kind of medicine is likely to be needed at this time.
那這個時候很可能需要用到這樣的藥
I'll come here first, okay?
我來這邊先好不好
That's what I want to ask, I just talked about SARS
就是我想要請問就是剛剛講SARS
It is because of the strong inflammation that destroys
是因為引起很強的發炎才會破壞
The tissue of the lungs means SARS
肺部的組織那意思是說就是SARS
The disease itself is not because the virus is too strong
本身這個疾病不是因為他病毒太強的
It's because of the inflammatory response he caused
是因為他引起的發炎反應才會就是
Does it harm the human body? If you want something else, just ask again.
對人體有傷害嘛然後想要另外就是再問說
Does he have any other diseases like SARS
他有沒有什麼其他的疾病是像SARS這樣子
Thank you, good question, that's exactly what it looks like
謝謝,很好問題,那就是確實這樣子
Is his virus particularly strong? It's hard to say
他的病毒是不是特別強,就是很難講
Because it is completely determined by who is our body
因為是完全是看誰是我們身體來決定
right , or that in this case
對不對,或是說是那在這個情況下
His at least we know is the cause of death
他的至少我們知道是造成死亡的原因
It's because our body reacts too strongly
是因為我們的身體的反應太強
What part of our body sees him
是我們身體看到他什麼部分
Why do you know it's a virus
為什麼知道是這個病毒
different from other viruses
跟另外病毒不一樣
so we want more reactions
所以我們要更多的反應
to be able to resist, to be able to resist
才能夠抵抗得到 抵抗得了
is it because of this
是不是因為這樣子
I guess this aspect is not so clear
我想這方面不是那麼清楚
We are just down to the end result
我們只是到最後的結果
it is indeed the cause of the final death
它確實是造成最後死亡的原因
or the cause of the sickness
或是造成病狠的原因
because we react a little too much
是因為我們的反應太多了一點
but we have no control
但是我們沒有控制
we didn't say yes
我們沒有說是
If the same person doesn't react so much
如果同一個人他反應沒有那麼多的話
will there be a problem
是不是會有問題
there is a problem not sure
有問題不太確定
remind me of a
讓我想到一個
I didn't mention it
我沒有提就是
If we know more about this
如果我們對這方面了解更多的話
In fact, these self-supporting organisms
事實上這些自生物自濟以後
maybe useful
說不定有用
We know what's in SARS
我們知道SARS裡面是什麼東西
Cause this Sidecans stone
造成這個Sidecans stone
words we now know
我們現在知道的話
Then prevention is
那以後預防就是
Now I hear in the Middle East
現在聽說在中東
It seems that there are several cases
好像有幾個case
It seems that there are 45 cases
好像有45個case
Then two people in the family died
然後一家裡面有兩個人死亡
If there is another SARS
如果說下面又有一個SARS
If so
這樣來的話
Maybe Anti-TNF
說不定是Anti-TNF
Give a few injections, at that time, if you give it impromptu, maybe it will be useful
打幾針,在那個時候,即興的時候打的話,說不定會有用
Is it right, and these two questions are
是不是,還有這兩個問題是
Are there any other diseases similar to SARS?
還有沒有其他的疾病也是類似像SARS這樣
I think liver cancer is liver cancer
我想肝癌就是肝癌
It is HEP-10, heterosexual hepatitis
就是HEP-10,異性肝炎
In the beginning, especially type A, it's not chronic
剛開始的時候,尤其是A型的話,它不是慢性的
When it's improvised, it's kind of causing physical sickness
即興的時候,它有些造成身體的發病
actually an inflammatory response
事實上是發炎的反應
There's a problem here, come on, from here, wait on this side
這邊有一個問題,來,從這邊起,等一下在這一邊
I'm talking to the general public, please ask
我是跟一般民眾,請教一下
Just now the president mentioned that some people have immune systems
剛剛那個總統有提到說,有些人是免疫系統
If it is stimulated by some foreign materials and causes damage, it will produce immunity
如果受到有些外來物資刺激,產生破壞,會產生免疫
It is IG1, which accepts the chemical cognition that produces certain specific stimuli
就是IG1,接受產生某些具體的刺激的化學認知
then it will put the layered runny race, eye rewrite
那麼會把分層流鼻水比賽,眼睛重寫
just some people wrong
正好有些人毛病
fault
毛病
I want to ask the director
我想請教所長
can be specific
可以具體來講說
The stimulus of foreign materials
外來物資的刺激
which aspect
是指哪一方面的
Is it the stimulation of foreign materials?
外來物資的刺激嗎
Okay, thank you
好 謝謝
I just wrote an allergen
就是我剛才寫了一個過敏源
Allergens are all around us
過敏源就是我們周遭的
like pollen
比如說花粉
then drugs
然後藥物
and dusty
還有塵滿這些
are foreign
都是外來的
these words
這些的話
In fact, even if we can eat it
事實上是我們即使可以吃進去
none of us will have a problem
我們都不會有什麼問題的
especially if say
尤其是如果說
If we don't have such a sensitive constitution
我們沒有這種敏感的體質的話
these we will react to it
這些我們對它會有反應
but not sensitive
但是也不會造成敏感
but some people
但就是有某些人
His physique is like this
他的體質是這樣子
maybe it has something to do with clothes
也許是跟衣穿有關
just accept this time
就是接受到這個時候
Our body has a reaction to it
我們身體對它是有一種反應
The result of the reaction produces IGE
反應的結果產生IGE
IGE in turn causes sensitive
IGE又造成敏感的
It's just that you just said that you have these symptoms
就是你剛講說你有這些症狀
That's because IGE
那就是因為IGE
I take the same pollen of these I don't generate IG
我接受同樣的這些花粉的這些我不產生IG
But you generate IG, the difference is here like this
但是你產生IG,差別在這裡這樣子
this is what these are humlist
這個就是這些都是humlist
It should be that we don't need to specifically react to it
應該是我們不需要特別去對它有反應
but we are responsive
但是我們是有反應的
And in some people, its reaction is to cause IG
而在某些人裡面,它的反應是造成IG的
sensitive
反應就會有敏感
It's probably as simple as this
大概簡單就這樣子
And it's usually possible to go
而且通常一般也是可以去
Really have an allergic reaction to this allergist when it bothers you a lot
真的對這個過敏員產生過敏反應對你長得很困擾的時候
You can take a test to see which allergies you are allergic to
你可以去測試看你自己是對哪些過敏員
is an allergic reaction
是會產生過敏反應的
It can also help you do some tests for general immunology and epidemiology
一般的免疫風勢科它也可以幫忙你做一些檢測
As mentioned earlier, some people are allergic to
像剛才講的有些人對發生會過敏
But some people most people don't
但是有些人大部分人都不會
So everyone's physique is different
所以這個每一個人體質不太一樣
here is another question please
這邊還有一個問題來請
Thanks
謝謝
I'm sorry, Director Liu, does liver muscle function have anything to do with allergies?
對不起 劉所長 肝肌能的好壞跟過敏有沒有關係
The second question is to say
第二個問題就是說
Recently, someone commented that eating good bacteria, probiotics or bacteria
最近有在留言說吃好的菌 益生菌 或者是菌
So does this good bacteria help reduce allergies?
所以這個菌好的對減少過敏有沒有幫助
Thanks
謝謝
I'm not sure about the allergy just now.
剛剛跟過敏的關係 我不太確定
I think this about our human body
我想這個我們的人體的話
It's the systemic symptoms I just talked about
就是我剛講說全身性的這種系統的症狀
So I can't say that what I do will not affect other people.
所以不能講說乾的不會影響到其他的
I think it is possible
我覺得是可能
But I can't think of any information on this
但是我想不出來有沒有這方面的資料
As for what you just said, it is
至於說是你剛講的那個什麼就是是
I guess if I only know what's right it's
我想如果說我只了解對的話就是
Like things like Lexlectropacillus
比如說Lexlectropacillus這種東西
that's what i asked me to write
那這就是我讓我寫寫寫的就是
thought I just mentioned that we now
想到說我剛剛提到說我們現在
It seems that the sensitivity is getting more and more, and the allergies are getting more and more
好像敏感越來越多 過敏越來越多
So why is this like this? There are different theories.
那這個為什麼這樣子呢 有不同的理論
There's a theory that we're getting cleaner
有個理論就是我們現在越來越乾淨
So we are the first to go up during development
所以我們就是最早上 在發育過程中
we are not exposed to germs
我們沒有接觸到細菌
Bacteria I just answered a question
細菌我剛剛有回答一個問題
I'm making it a little more professional
是我把它講的稍微專業化一點
That is, we see that the usual response of bacteria is to
就是我們看到細菌通常的反應是
Type 1 T cells respond to TH1
第一型的T細胞的反應TH1
That's what we just said
那邊的話就是我們剛剛有講過
For our Ellogy, TH2 is the second type
我們的Ellogy的話TH2就第二型的
If it is your body that produces Type 1
如果說是你的身體是產生第一型的話
The second type will be less like this
那第二型就會少一點這樣子
So according to this
所以根據這個的話
Just want to say if we let our body come
就想說我們是不是讓我們身體來
to get in touch with this thing like a virus
來接觸到這個像病毒這些東西
It's bacteria
就是細菌這些
Then let's generate a comparison of the first type
那就讓我們產生比較第一型的
and just like that
而就這樣
there is no second line
第二行就沒有
but i guess it's a thought
但是我想這是一種想法
so is it because of this
因此是不是因為這個
just to get some people to start trying this
才讓有些人開始試這個
But what this does in this regard is
但這個在這方面做的是
try a lot
試有不少
doing this
在做這方面
some seem to work
有些看起來有效
some don't seem to work
有些看起來沒有效
so no conclusion yet
所以還沒有定論
Is it possible to use this to treat
就是是不是可以用這個來治療
these allergies
這些過敏
not entirely clear
並不完全清楚
But this also mentions
但是這個另外有提到
Just what I just said is clean
就是跟我剛才講的乾淨
It doesn't matter
這些沒有關係就是
I just mentioned the skin
我剛提到過皮膚上面
Maybe you didn't imagine
也許你們沒有想像的
think we have thousands
想到我們有數千
Thousands of these
上千上萬的這種
not thousands
不是上千上萬個
but thousands of kinds
而是上千上萬種的
sexual exercise here
行性運動這裡
Our name is micropeiota
我們叫micropeiota
That's what we do
那乾的就是在我們的
the same in the intestines
腸裡面也是一樣
I say this theory
那這個理論我說
Put this other this like
把這個另外這個像
After eating Lactopacillus
Lactopacillus吃進去以後
will appear to that
就會對那個會出現
Those microphone towers inside will affect the
會裡面的那些麥克風比喻塔會影響到
Affect those microphone towers
影響到 那些麥克風比喻塔
Affects our body's immune response
會影響到我們身體的免疫反應
it's amazing so quantum maybe
這很奇妙的 所以量子也許
Through that relationship it affects this allergy
經過那個關係把它影響到這個過敏
Maybe it's a possibility, that comparison is a little more complicated
也許有這個可能性 那個比較稍微複雜一點
I just mentioned the allergic reaction between SARS and the new arrival
就是剛剛有提到那個SARS跟剛來的過敏反應
Then I want to ask now because it has been seen clinically
那我現在想要問一下 因為在臨床上有看到
Genital cystitis, then I want to ask
建殖性膀胱炎 那我想問一下
This is also related to the allergic reaction
這是跟那個過敏反應也是有關
I don't know what this is called
這個我不知道不太清楚是什麼叫什麼
how are you explaining
怎麼樣 你在說明嗎
TiCa then genital cystitis
TiCa 然後建殖性膀胱炎
Long-term is like cystitis
長期就是會像膀胱炎
you're thinking about that
對 這個你在想說那個
Yes, just name it
對,名字一下就行
I don't think that has anything to do with allergies
我想那個跟過敏沒有關係
it doesn't matter, yes
沒有關係,對
It has nothing to do with the so-called allergies
跟所謂的過敏是沒有關係
But what you say must matter
但是發言的話一定是有關係的
speaking is relevant
發言是有關係的
next question, come on, please
後面的問題,來,請
that is
就是
microphone, click
麥克風,按一下
green
綠色的
May I?
可以嗎?
I want to ask the director
我想請教所長
Because I am a student of Xinzhuang Shixiep University
因為我是新莊士協大學的學員
two are
二位是
Come to politics after surgery
來政經過手術
After surgery, my hand now often
手術以後我現在的手常常會
the forearm often speaks
前手臂常會發言
If there is one more symptom before the speech, it will occur first
發言以前的話多一個症狀,就先發生
eruption
汗泡疹
Sweat herpes followed by speech
汗泡疹以後接著就發言
I want to ask
我想請教
this
這個
that sweat herpes is
那個汗泡疹是
how
怎樣
how and why happened
怎樣為什麼會發生
how to reduce how often it happens
如何降低它發生的頻率
Then keep doing this many times, will it affect
然後一直這樣子很多次這樣子會不會影響
Please bring up other sequelae
請起其他的後遺症
Thanks
謝謝
Sorry, my Chinese is not very clear
不好意思我這個中文又是不太清楚
Han Leopard Clinic
漢豹診
Herbis bar
Herbis吧
English is
英文是
there is now
現在就有
have it now
現在手上就有
Han Leopard Clinic
漢豹診
no
不是
wait and see how you are
等一下再看看你的狀況
right
對
I need to know more now
我現在要多了解一下
I want to ask the director
我想請教所長
I'm a high school student at Yan Ping Middle School
我是嚴平中學的高中生
I am very interested in biology
我本身就對生物非常有興趣
I read it in my school biology textbook
我之前在學校的生物課本上面看到說
When pathogens invade the human body
病原體入侵人體的時候
The human immune system can
人體的免疫系統可以從
Thousands of B cells, NT cells
成千上萬的B細胞、NT細胞中
Select the one corresponding to the pathogen to deal with him
選出和病原體相對應的來對付他
Then what I want to ask the director is
那我想請教所長的就是
How to choose the human immune system
人體的免疫系統要怎麼選擇
Thanks
謝謝
I think your enough is probably a function of extremely strong cells
我想你足夠的很可能就是極壯細胞的功能
I just said that the extremely strong cells are the last generals
我剛講過極壯細胞是最後的總帥
He'll tear viruses or foreign matter into it.
他會把病毒或是外面來的物質撕進去
Then he'll come back out
然後他再會退土出來
Then this makes the T cell the T cell just mentioned
然後這個就讓T cell就是剛講的T細胞
At the beginning of the T cells, there is no need to know what will affect them
T細胞本身是剛開始的時候是沒有要知道對什麼東西有影響
but he will put this
但是他會把這個
So I just said above what kind of antigen is the cell that presents the antigen
所以我剛才上面有說是什麼抗原呈現抗原的細胞
Energy Presented Cell
Energy Presented Cell
He will let T cells Educate
他就會讓T細胞Educate
Only then will the T cells know
這樣的話T細胞才知道
He will have an effect on that antigen
他就會對那個抗原來作作有作用
Therefore, there was no exposure to this antigen at all.
所以本來是完全沒有接觸這個抗原情況下
T cells are all the same
T細胞是每個都是一樣的
But after the extremely strong cells penetrate this source
但極壯細胞把這個看源刺進去之後
it just shows up
它才呈現出來
Then let the T cell know which source it should look at
然後再讓T細胞知道說它應該對哪個看源來
such a selection process
就這樣的選擇過程
In other words, there are mathematical types of T cells to choose from.
或者說是有數學種T細胞來選
Rather, let certain cells
而說是讓某些細胞
adicate becomes that it can respond to that look at the source
adicate的變成它能夠針對那個看源來反應
The same goes for B cells
同樣B細胞也是一樣的
There was another question here just now, is it gone?
剛才這邊還有一個問題是不是沒有了
is there any problem
還有沒有什麼問題
ok our last question
好來我們最後一個問題
Ask our Deputy Director Li
請教我們的李副所長
Because you are also an expert in dermatology
因為您也是皮膚科的專家
we have a friend
我們有一個朋友
his skin
他那個皮膚
not clean
也不是乾淨
One piece of white, one piece of white on the face and hands
東一塊白 西一塊白 臉上 手上都有
Seen by many dermatologists
看很多皮膚科醫師都看不好
I want to ask the director
想請問一下所長
What is his disease and what is the cause?
他這個是什麼病什麼成因該
what's the difference
差什麼樣
Thanks
謝謝
see must
看到必須的
Are you talking about white spots?
你這講的是是不是白斑針嗎
White spot is called Bertar Ligo in English
白斑就是英文叫Bertar Ligo
Yes, Bertar Ligo
對,Bertar Ligo
that words
那個的話
not so easy to control
不是那麼容易控制
But the same goes for the liver, for example.
但是比如說肝也是一樣
illumination, illumination light
照光,照外線光
can treat most
是可以治療大部分
Where do some medicines look
有些藥看哪個地方
some medicine can rub
有些藥可以擦
In some cases, it responds quite well
有些情況下,它反應還蠻不錯的
right
對
He sees various dermatologists
他卻看皮膚各醫師
I read a lot and didn't think about it
看了很多都沒有想
served
上桌了
Then the other one is
然後另外一個就是
A relatively new development is
比較新的發展是
He wants cell transplantation, so it becomes stem cells
他要細胞胰植,所以就變成幹細胞
This is because his rate of fire cells don't
這邊是因為他的射速細胞沒有
So if you say it's pancreas
所以你如果說是胰植的話
he can recover
他可以再復原
so that is a way
所以那個是一個方式
For example, if the scope of influence is too large
比如說影響範圍太大的話
It's not conspiracy
倒是不是謀異
but later development
但是以後的發展
maybe from the dry bag perspective
可能是從幹西包的角度來做
just some people will react
就是有些人會有反應
some people will have
有些人會有
Just two is one on steroids
就是兩個就是一個類固醇
something else called
另外東西叫做
The product name in English is called Protopic
用英文的商品名叫做Protopic
Protopic
Protopic
The director finally asks you
所長最後請教你
that
那個
Is it related to allergies?
跟過敏有沒有關係
Are you allergic to dermatitis?
皮膚炎過敏是嗎
Significant dermatitis is skin
意味性皮膚炎就是皮膚
also considered allergic
也算過敏
Thanks
謝謝
So what is being said is
所以所講的是
To spot this part
要排斑這個部分
this is small
這個是算是小的
it's about the wife
這是跟太太有關
too sun
太太陽
He said it was more serious
他講那個是比較嚴重
bigger
比較大一點
This intentional eye relationship
這個有意眼關係
right
對
Generally
一般是
this may be
這個可能就
it's not easy
就不太容易了
He also said no
他也說沒有
good
好
we again
我們再一次
Thank you Chief Liu
謝謝劉首長
wonderful speech
很精彩的這一個演講
That
那
give me one last minute
最後給我一分鐘的時間
That's what we learned in December
就是我們12月份的知識
want to test
想驗
is up to us
是要由我們
China Cultural Responsibility Institute's
中國文責研究所的
Governance
理事學
The researcher wants to speak
研究員要來講
Our Vernacular Bible
我們的白話文聖經
is a rather interesting subject
是一個相當有趣的主題
so the time is in
所以時間呢是在
December 25th
12月25號
Tuesday night
星期二的晚上
also in this place
也是在這一個地方
to give a speech
來舉行演講
All are welcome to participate
歡迎各位能夠踴躍來參加
Thanks
謝謝